- Basically, this entire
roundtable session here
- 这整个圆桌会议
is just gonna be focused
mainly on prompt engineering.
主要将集中在提示工程上。
A variety of perspectives at
this table around prompting
在桌子上的各种视角围绕提示
from a research side,
from a consumer side,
从研究方面，
从消费者方面，
and from the enterprise side.
以及企业方面展开。
And I want to just get the
whole wide range of opinions
我想就整个范围的意见
because there's a lot of them.
因为有很多不同的意见。
And just open it up to discussion
并且开放讨论以探索
and explore what prompt
engineering really is
提示工程到底是什么
and what it's all about.
以及它涉及到什么。
And yeah, we'll just take it from there.
好的，我们就从这里开始吧。
So maybe we can go around
the horn with intros.
或许我们可以绕过障碍，以自我介绍的形式进行交流。
I can kick it off. I'm Alex.
我可以先开始。我是亚历克斯。
I lead Developer Relations
here at Anthropic.
我在Anthropic负责开发者关系。
Before that,
在那之前，
I was technically a prompt
engineer at Anthropic.
我实际上是一名来自Anthropic的提示工程师。
I worked on our prompt engineering team,
我在我们的提示工程团队工作。
and did a variety of roles spanning
并担任了各种角色跨越
from a solutions architect type of thing,
从架构师的角度来看，
to working on the research side.
从事研究工作。
So with that, maybe I can
hand it over to David.
- Heck, yeah. My name's David Hershey.
所以这样，或许我可以把话筒递给大卫。
I work with customers mostly at Anthropic
- 简单说，我叫大卫·赫舍尔。
on a bunch of stuff technical,
我在安德鲁皮克公司主要与客户合作，
I help people with finetuning,
处理各种技术问题，
but also just a lot of the generic things
帮助人们进行微调，
that make it hard to adopt
language models of prompting.
但更多的是帮助解决采用语言模型提示的通用问题。
And just like how to build
systems with language models,
就像如何使用语言模型构建系统，
but spend most of my time
working with customers.
但我大部分时间都在与客户打交道。
- Cool. I'm Amanda Askell.
- 很酷。我是阿曼达·阿斯卡尔。
I lead one of the Finetuning
teams at Anthropic,
我在Anthropic的一个微调团队中担任领导。
where I guess I try to make
Claude be honest and kind.
我在试图让克劳德诚实和善良。
Yeah.
好的。
- My name is Zack Witten.
我叫扎克·温特。
I'm a Prompt Engineer at Anthropic.
我在Anthropic担任Prompt工程师。
Alex and I always argue
about who the first one was.
我和亚历克斯总是争论谁是第一个。
He says it's him, I say it's me.
他说是他，我说是我。
- Contested.
- Yeah.
争议中。
是的。
I used to work a lot with
individual customers,
我以前经常与个人客户打交道，
kind of the same way David does now.
就像大卫现在所做的那样。
And then as we brought
more solutions architects
然后当我们带来了更多的解决方案架构师
to the team, I started working on things
给团队成员，我开始着手做事情了。
that are meant to raise the overall levels
旨在提高整体水平的那些
of ambient prompting in society,
社会中的环境提示
I guess, like the prompt generator
我觉得，就像提示生成器一样
and the various educational
materials that people use.
以及人们使用的各种教育资源。
- Nice, cool. Well, thanks
guys for all coming here.
好的，非常棒。谢谢大家来参加。
I'm gonna start with a very broad question
我先从一个非常宽泛的问题开始。
just so we have a frame
为了有一个框架
going into the rest of
our conversations here.
进入我们在这里的其他对话。
What is prompt engineering?
Why is it engineering?
什么是提示工程？
为什么它是工程？
What's prompt, really?
什么是真正的提示？
If anyone wants to kick that off,
如果有人想先开始的话，
give your own perspective on it,
谈谈你自己的看法。
feel free to take the rein here.
你随时可以接管。
- I feel like we have a prompt engineer.
我觉得我们有一个提示工程师。
It's his job.
这是他的工作。
- We're all prompt
engineers in our own form.
我们都是自己形式的提示工程师。
- But one of us has a job.
但是我们其中一个人有工作。
- Yeah. Zack, maybe
since it's in your title.
- 嗯。扎克，或许是因为你在标题里用了这个名字吧。
- One of us has a job, but the
other three don't have jobs.
我们当中有一个有工作，但其他三个都没有工作。
- I guess I feel like prompt engineering
我觉得我像是在做提示工程。
is trying to get the model to do things,
正在尝试让模型去做事。
trying to bring the most out of the model.
试图从模型中榨取最大价值。
Trying to work with the
model to get things done
试图与模型合作完成任务。
that you wouldn't have
been able to do otherwise.
那否则你无法做到。
So a lot of it is just
clear communicating.
所以主要就是
清楚沟通。
I think at heart,
我认为根本上，
talking to a model is a lot
like talking to a person.
与模型对话就像与人对话。
And getting in there
进入其中
and understanding the
psychology of the model,
并理解模型的心理学，
which Amanda is the world's
most expert person in the world.
哪位Amanda是世界上最擅长的人。
- Well, I'm gonna keep going on you.
- 好的，我还要继续逗你。
Why is engineering in the name?
为什么工程以这个名字？
- Yeah.
好的。
I think the engineering part
comes from the trial and error.
我认为工程部分是通过试错得来的。
- Okay.
好的。
- So one really nice thing
about talking to a model
与模型对话真是太好了。
that's not like talking to a person,
这不像在和一个人说话。
is you have this restart button.
你有这个重启按钮吗？
This giant go back to square zero
这头巨兽归零了
where you just start from the beginning.
从头开始。
And what that gives you the ability to do
这赋予你做什么能力的
that you don't have, is a
truly start from scratch
没有的东西， truly 是从头开始。
and try out different things
in an independent way,
然后以独立的方式尝试不同的事情。
so that you don't have
interference from one to the other.
以便彼此之间没有干扰。
And once you have that
ability to experiment
一旦你有了这种实验的能力
and to design different things,
以及设计不同的事物，
that's where the engineering
part has the potential
那是工程部分有潜力的地方。
to come in.
到场
- Okay.
好的。
So what you're saying is as
you're writing these prompts,
你正在写这些提示时，
you're typing in a message
to Claude or in the API
你在给Claude写消息或使用API
or whatever it is.
或者是什么东西。
Being able to go back
and forth with the model
能与模型来回交流
and to iterate on this message,
并在此基础上进行迭代，
and revert back to the
clean slate every time,
并且每次都要回到一个干净的起点。
that process is the engineering part.
那个过程是工程部分。
This whole thing is prompt
engineering all in one.
这整套东西都是集成化工程。
- There's another aspect of it too,
此外还有一个方面。
which is integrating the prompts
就是将提示词整合在一起
within your system as a whole.
在整个系统中。
And David has done a ton of
work with customers integrating.
大卫在与客户集成方面做了大量的工作。
A lot of times it's not just as simple
很多时候并不是那么简单。
as you write one prompt and
you give it to the model
当你写一个提示并把它给模型时
and you're done.
就这样结束了。
In fact, it's anything but.
It's like way more complicated.
实际上，这远比你想象的要复杂得多。
- Yeah.
好的。
I think of prompts as the way
我认为提示是引导
that you program models a little bit,
你稍微编程一下。
that makes it too complicated.
这太复杂了。
'Cause I think Zack is generally right
因为我觉得扎克通常是对的。
that it's just talking clearly
is the most important thing.
那就是说话要清晰。
But if you think about it a little bit
但如果你稍微想想
as programming a model,
you have to think about
作为编程模型，
你需要考虑
where data comes from, what
data you have access to.
数据的来源是什么，你能够访问哪些数据。
So if you're doing RAG or something,
所以如果你在做RAG或者类似的事情，
what can I actually use
and do and pass to a model?
我实际上可以使用、做和传递给模型什么？
You have to think about
trade-offs in latency
你必须考虑延迟权衡。
and how much data you're
providing and things like that.
以及你提供多少数据等问题。
There's enough systems thinking
that goes into how you
actually build around a model.
有足够多的系统思维
I think a lot of that's also the core
在你实际上围绕一个模型构建时。
of why it maybe deserves
its own carve-out as a thing
我认为，这很多也是为什么它可能有资格
to reason about separately
from just a software engineer
作为一个独立的事物来考虑，
or a PM or something like that.
而不仅仅是软件工程师或项目经理之类的人。
It's kind of its own domain
它本质上是一个关于如何思考这些模型
of how to reason about these models.
自己的领域。
- Is a prompt in this sense
then natural language code?
- 这里的提示是不是自然语言代码？
Is it a higher level of abstraction
是否是一种更高层次的抽象
or is it a separate thing?
或者是一个单独的事情？
- I think trying to get too
abstract with a prompt is a way
我认为在提示中过于抽象化是一种方式
to overcomplicate a
thing, because I think,
过度复杂一个事情，因为我认为，
we're gonna get into it,
but more often than not,
我们会陷入其中的，但很多时候，
the thing you wanna do
你想要做的事情
is just write a very clear
description of a task,
只是写一个非常清晰的任务描述，
not try to build crazy
abstractions or anything like that.
而不是尝试构建复杂的抽象或类似的东西。
But that said, you are compiling
the set of instructions
但是说到底，你在编译指令集
and things like that into
outcomes a lot of times.
和各种事情上将这些编译成结果。
So precision and a lot the things
所以精确度和许多事情
you think about with programming
about version control
你用编程思考的是版本控制。
and managing what it looked like
并且管理它的外观
back then when you had this experiment.
那时你做这个实验。
And tracking your experiment
and stuff like that,
以及跟踪你的实验
that's all just equally important to code.
那只是与代码一样重要。
- Yeah.
嗯。
- So it's weird to be in this
paradigm where written text,
所以在这个文字为王的 paradigm 里，
like a nice essay that
you wrote is something
像你写的一篇好作文一样
that's looked like the same thing as code.
那看起来像是同样的代码。
But it is true that now we write essays
但是现在我们写文章。
and treat them code, and I
think that's actually correct.
并且把它们当作代码处理，我觉得这是正确的。
- Yeah. Okay, interesting.
好的，很有趣。
So maybe piggybacking off of that,
也许可以搭着这个顺风车。
we've loosely defined what
prompt engineering is.
我们松散地定义了什么是提示工程。
So what makes a good prompt engineer?
什么是好的提示工程师？
Maybe, Amanda, I'll go to you for this,
也许，安德烈亚，这个问题我找你来解决。
since you're trying to
hire prompt engineers
因为你正在尝试雇佣prompt工程师
more so in a research setting.
在研究环境中尤为如此。
What does that look like?
那看起来是什么样子？
What are you looking for
in that type of person?
你对那种人
有什么期待？
- Yeah, good question.
好的问题。
I think it's a mix of like
Zack said, clear communication,
我觉得是沟通不畅。
so the ability to just
clearly state things,
所以能够清楚地表达事情，
clearly understand tasks,
明确任务。
think about and describe
concepts really well.
好好思考和描述概念。
That's the writing component, I think.
那应该是写字的部分。
I actually think that being a good writer
我实际上认为成为一个好的作家
is not as correlated with
being a good prompt engineer
不那么与
成为一个好的提示工程师
相关联
as people might think.
正如人们所认为的那样。
So I guess I've had this
discussion with people
所以我猜我已经和人们讨论过这个问题。
'cause I think there's
some argument as like,
因为我觉得有点像在争论。
"Maybe you just shouldn't have
the name engineer in there.
你可能不应该在那儿叫工程师。
Why isn't it just writer?"
为什么不只是作家？
I used to be more sympathetic to that.
我以前更同情那个。
And then, I think, now I'm like
what you're actually doing,
然后，我想我现在就像你在做什么。
people think that you're writing
one thing and you're done.
人们认为你写了一件事就完事了。
Then I'll be like to
get a semi-decent prompt
然后我就想得到一个不错的提示。
when I sit down with the model.
当我坐在模型旁。
Earlier, I was prompting the model
刚才我在提示模型
and I was just like in a 15-minute span
而我在15分钟内就完成了。
I'll be sending hundreds
of prompts to the model.
我将向模型发送数百个提示。
It's just back and forth, back
and forth, back and forth.
它只是来来回回，来回，再来来回。
So I think it's this willingness
to iterate and to look
所以我认为这是这种愿意迭代和尝试的心态。
and think what is it that
was misinterpreted here,
以及想想这里有什么被误解了。
if anything?
如果有什么问题？
And then fix that thing.
然后把这个东西修好。
So that ability to iterate.
所以迭代的能力。
So I'd say clear communication,
that ability to iterate.
所以我说明确的沟通，
迭代的能力。
I think also thinking about ways
我想也思考一下方法。
in which your prompt might go wrong.
在你的提示可能出错的地方。
So if you have a prompt
所以如果你有一个提示
that you're going to be
applying to say, 400 cases,
你将申请说有400个案例，
it's really easy to think
about the typical case
真容易想到常见的情况。
that it's going to be applied to,
它将要应用于
to see that it gets the
right solution in that case,
看出它在那种情况下能得到正确的解决方案。
and then to move on.
然后继续前进。
I think this is a very classic
mistake that people made.
我觉得这是一个非常经典的人类错误。
What you actually want
to do is find the cases
你实际上想做的就是找到案例。
where it's unusual.
在那里很不寻常。
So you have to think about
your prompt and be like,
所以你必须考虑你的提示，并且要像这样：
"What are the cases where
it'd be really unclear to me
什么情况下会让我真的无法确定
what I should do in this case?"
在这种情况下我该怎么办？
So for example, you
have a prompt that says,
所以，比如你有一个提示说，
"I'm going to send you a bunch of data.
我将向你发送一批数据。
I want you to extract all of the rows
我想让你提取所有行
where someone's name is, I don't know,
谁的名字我不知道，
starts with the letter G."
以字母G开头。
And then you're like, "Well,
I'm gonna send it a dataset
然后你就说：“好吧，
我 gonna 发送一个数据集
where there is no such thing,
那里没有这样的东西。
there is no such name that
starts with the letter G.
没有以字母G开头的名字。
"I'm going to send it
something that's not a dataset,
"I要发送一些不是数据集的东西，
I might also just send it an empty string.
我可能会直接发送一个空字符串。
These are all of the
cases you have to try,
这些是你必须尝试的所有情况，
because then you're like, "What
does it do in these cases? "
因为你需要问自己，“在这种情况下它会做什么？ ”
And then you can give it more instructions
然后你可以给出更多的指示，
for how it should deal with that case.
说明它应该如何处理这种情况。
- I work with customers so
often where you're an engineer,
- 我经常和客户合作，他们通常都是工程师，
you're building something.
正在构建一些东西。
And there's a part in your
prompt where a customer of theirs
在你的提示中有一个部分，
is going to write something.
客户的某个部分将要写些什么。
- Yeah.
好的。
- And they all think
- 而他们所有人都认为
about these really
perfectly phrased things
关于这些真的
完美表达的事物
that they think someone's going
to type into their chatbot.
他们认为有人会在他们的聊天机器人中输入内容。
And in reality, it's like
they never used the shift key
实际上，就像他们从未使用过换行键一样。
and every other word is a typo.
并且每个其他单词都是拼写错误。
- They think it's Google.
- And there's no punctuation.
- 他们认为是谷歌。
- 没有标点符号。
- They just put in random
words with no question.
他们只是随口胡说，没有任何问题。
- Exactly.
对的。
So you have these evals
所以你有这些评估。
that are these beautifully structured
那就是这些优雅结构的
what their users ideally would type in.
用户理想上想要输入的内容。
But being able to go the next step
但是能够迈出下一步
to reason about what your
actual traffic's gonna be like,
来推断你的实际流量会是什么样子的，
what people are actually
gonna to try to do,
人们实际上会尝试做的事情。
that's a different level of thinking.
那是不同的思维方式。
- One thing you said that
really resonated with me
你有一句话真的触动了我。
is reading the model responses.
在阅读模型的回复。
In a machine learning context,
在机器学习的背景下，
you're supposed to look at the data.
你应该看数据。
It's almost a cliche
like look at your data,
这几乎是一个陈词滥调，就像看看你的数据。
and I feel like the
equivalent for prompting
我觉得这是提示的等价物。
is look at the model outputs.
看看模型的输出。
Just reading a lot of outputs
and reading them closely.
只是多读一些输出，并仔细阅读。
Like Dave and I were
talking on the way here,
就像我和Dave在这里的路上讨论的那样，
one thing that people will do
人们会做一件事。
is they'll put think
step-by-step in their prompt.
他们会一步步地在提示中思考。
And they won't check to make sure
他们不会检查确保的。
that the model is actually
thinking step-by-step,
模型实际上是在一步一步地思考。
because the model might
take it in a more abstract
因为模型可能会将其理解为一个更抽象的概念。
or general sense.
或者一般理解。
Rather than like,
不如
"No, literally you have to
write down your thoughts
不，你必须写下你的想法。
in these specific tags."
在这些特定的标签中。
So yeah, if you aren't
reading the model outputs,
所以，如果你不读取模型输出，
you might not even notice
that it's making that mistake.
你可能根本不会注意到
它正在犯那个错误。
- Yeah, that's interesting.
- 哦，这很有趣。
There is that weird theory of mind piece
有那种奇怪的意识理论。
to being a prompt engineer
成为提示工程师
where you have to think almost about
你几乎要想到
how the model's gonna
view your instructions.
模型会如何看待你的指令。
But then if you're writing for
an enterprise use case too,
但如果你是在为一个企业应用场景编写代码，
you also have to think about
你还要考虑
how the user's gonna talk to the model,
用户如何与模型交流，
as you're the third party sitting there
因为你是个旁观者坐在那里
in that weird relationship.
在这个奇怪的关系中。
Yeah.
好的。
- On the theory of mind piece,
one thing I would say is,
在关于心智理论的文章中，我想说的是，
it's so hard to write
instructions down for a task.
写任务的说明真的很难。
It's so hard to untangle in your own brain
在你自己的脑子里理清这些真是太难了。
all of the stuff that you know
你知道的所有东西
that Claude does not
know and write it down.
那是因为Claude不知道并写不下来。
It's just an immensely challenging thing
这仅仅是一个极其困难的事情。
to strip away all of the
assumptions you have, and be able
去除所有假设，并能够
to very clearly communicate the
full fact set of information
非常清楚地传达完整的信息集
that is needed to a model.
这是构建模型所需的内容。
I think that's another thing
我觉得那是另一件事。
that really differentiates
a good prompt engineer
那真正区别了
一个优秀的提示工程师
from a bad one, is like...
从一个糟糕的开始，就像...
A lot of people will just write
down the things they know.
很多人只会写下他们知道的东西。
But they don't really take the time
但他们真的没有足够的时间。
to systematically break out
系统性突破
what is the actual full set of
information you need to know
你需要了解的实际完整信息是什么？
to understand this task?
了解这个任务吗？
- Right.
好的。
- And that's a very
clear thing I see a lot
而且这是我经常看到的非常清楚的一件事。
is prompts where it's just conditioned.
指令是条件化的。
The prompt that someone
wrote is so conditioned
某人写的提示语条件反射太强
on their prior understanding of a task,
基于他们对任务的理解，
that when they show it to me
I'm like, "This makes no sense.
当他们向我展示时，我就像说，“这完全不通。
None of the words you
wrote make any sense,
你写的所有单词都没有意义。
because I don't know anything
因为我什么都不懂。
about your interesting use case."
关于你有趣的用例。
But I think a good way to
think about prompt engineering
但是我认为思考提示工程的一个好方法是
in that front and a good skill for it,
在这个方面表现良好，并且具备相关的技能。
is just can you actually
step back from what you know
只是你能不能后退一步，超越你的知识？
and communicate to this weird
system that knows a lot,
并且与这个知道很多的奇怪系统进行沟通。
but not everything about what
it needs to know to do a task?
但是一切它需要知道才能完成任务的内容吗？
- Yeah.
好的。
The amount of times I've
seen someone's prompt
我见过某人提示的次数
and then being like,
然后就像这样，
"I can't do the task
based on this prompt."
我不能基于这个提示完成任务。
I'm human level and you're
giving this to something
我是人类水平，而你正在把这交给一个东西。
that is worse than me and
expecting it to do better,
那比我还差，并且期待它能做得更好。
and I'm like, "Yeah."
“嗯。”
- Yeah.
好的。
There is that interesting
thing with like...
有趣的是……
Current models don't really do a good job
现在的模型真的做得不好。
of asking good, probing
questions in response
对提出好问题作出回应
like a human would.
像人类一样。
If I'm giving Zack directions
on how to do something,
如果我在给扎克发指令做某件事，
he'll be like, "This
doesn't make any sense.
他会说，“这没有什么意义。”
What am I supposed to do at
this step or here and here?"
我该在这个步骤或这里和那里做什么？
Model doesn't do that, right,
so you have to, as yourself,
模型做不到这一点，对吧，
所以你必须自己做。
think through what that
other person would say
想想那个另一个人会说什么。
and then go back to your prompt
and answer those questions.
然后回到你的提示中，回答这些问题。
- You could ask it to do that.
你可以让它这样做。
- You could. That's right.
- I do that, yeah.
你可以说。没错。
我就是这样做的。
- I guess that's another step.
我想那是又一步。
- I was going to say one
of the first things I do
我要说的第一件事是
with my initial prompt,
在第一次提示中，
is I'll give it the prompt
and then I'll be like,
我会给你提示，然后我就会说，
"I don't want you to
follow these instructions.
我不希望你遵循这些指示。
I just want you to tell me the ways in
我只想让你告诉我进入的方法。
which they're unclear or any ambiguities,
他们对此不明确或有任何模糊之处。
or anything you don't understand."
或者你不懂的任何东西。
And it doesn't always get it perfect,
它并不总是完全正确。
but it is interesting that
that is one thing you can do.
但有趣的是，你可以这样做。
And then also sometimes if people see
而且有时候如果人们看到
that the model makes a mistake,
模型犯了错误，
the thing that they don't
often do is just ask the model.
他们很少做的事情就是直接问模型。
So they say to the model,
"You got this wrong.
所以他们告诉模型，“你弄错了。”
Can you think about why?
你能想想为什么吗？
And can you maybe write an
edited version of my instructions
并且你能 maybe 写一个编辑版本的我的指令，
that would make you not get it wrong?"
这样就不会再出错了？”
And a lot of the time, the
model just gets it right.
很多时候，模型都会把事情做对。
The model's like, "Oh, yeah.
模型说，“哦，是的。
Here's what was unclear, here's
a fix to the instructions,"
这里有点不清楚，这里有修正指令”，
and then you put those in and it works.
然后你就把这些放在里面，它就 works。
- Okay.
好的。
I'm actually really curious
about this personally almost.
我其实对这件事非常好奇。
Is that true that that works?
真的吗？那能行吗？
Is the model able to spot
its mistakes that way?
这个模型通过这种方式能发现它的错误吗？
When it gets something wrong, you say,
当它做错事时，你说，
"Why did you get this wrong?"
你为什么会答错？
And then it tells you
maybe something like,
然后它告诉你
也许会有些类似于
"Okay, how could I phrase
this to you in the future
好的，我以后该怎么向你表达呢？
so you get it right?"
所以你弄明白了？
Is there an element of truth to that?
这有几分道理吗？
Or is that just a hallucination
on the model's part
或者这只是模型的幻觉
around what it thinks its limits are?
围绕它认为自己的极限是什么？
- I think if you explain
to it what it got wrong,
我认为如果向它解释它犯了什么错，
it can identify things
in the query sometimes.
它有时能识别查询中的事物。
I think this varies by task.
我觉得这因任务而异。
This is one of those things
where I'm like I'm not sure
这是一些事情之一
我真不确定
what percentage of the
time it gets it right,
它猜对的频率是多少？
but I always try it
'cause sometimes it does.
但我不敢保证它会成功。
- And you learn something.
- Yeah.
- 你也会学到东西。
- 嗯。
- Anytime you go back to the model
- 你随时可以回到模型
or back and forth with the model,
或者与模型来回交流。
you learn something about what's going on.
你学到了一些关于正在发生的事情。
I think you're giving away information
我认为你在泄露信息。
if you don't at least try.
如果你至少尝试一下。
- That's interesting.
- 这很有趣。
Amanda, I'm gonna keep asking
you a few more questions here.
安德玛，我还要在这里问你几个问题。
One thing maybe for
everybody watching this,
对所有人观看的这一部分来说，
is we have these Slack
channels at Anthropic
我们有这些Slack频道在Anthropic
where people can add Claude
into the Slack channel,
人们可以将Claude添加到Slack频道中，
then you can talk to Claude through it.
然后你可以通过它与Claude交流。
And Amanda has a Slack channel
而安德玛有一个Slack频道
that a lot of people follow of
her interactions with Claude.
很多人都在关注她与克劳德的互动。
And one thing that I see
you always do in there,
我注意到你在那里总是会做的事情是
which you probably do the
most of anyone at Anthropic,
你可能是在Anthropic做最多的。
is use the model to help you
使用模型帮助你
in a variety of different scenarios.
在各种不同的场景中。
I think you put a lot
of trust into the model
我觉得你对模型寄托了太多的信任。
in the research setting.
在研究环境中。
I'm curious how you've
developed those intuitions
我对你是如何培养出这些直觉的很好奇。
for when to trust the model.
何时信任模型。
Is that just a matter of usage,
是不是用法的问题，
experience or is it something else?
- I think I don't trust the model ever
你有经验吗？还是其他什么？
and then I just hammer on it.
我觉得我永远都不信任这个模型。
So I think the reason why
you see me do that a lot,
然后我只是不断地敲打它。
is that that is me being like,
所以我认为这就是为什么你会看到我经常这样做，
"Can I trust you to do this task?"
因为那就像在问：
'Cause there's some things,
models are kind of strange.
“你能信任我完成这项任务吗？”
If you go slightly out of distribution,
因为有些事情，模型有点奇怪。
you just go into areas where
they haven't been trained
如果你稍微超出分布范围，
or they're unusual.
你就进入他们没有训练或不常见的领域。
Sometimes you're like,
有时候你会像是，
"Actually, you're much less reliable here,
“实际上，你在这里的可靠性要低得多，
even though it's a fairly simple task."
尽管这是一项相当简单的任务。”
I think that's happening
less and less over time
我认为这种情况随着时间越来越不常见
as models get better,
因为模型变得越来越好，
but you want to make sure you're
not in that kind of space.
但你需要确保自己不在那种空间里。
So, yeah, I don't think
I trust it by default,
所以，嗯，我不认为我默认信任它，
but I think in ML,
但在机器学习中，
people often want to look
across really large datasets.
人们通常想跨非常大的数据集进行操作。
And I'm like, "When does
it make sense to do that?"
我说：“什么时候这样做才有意义？”
And I think the answer is when
you get relatively low signal
我觉得答案是当你信号相对较低时
from each data point,
从每个数据点，
you want to look across
many, many data points,
你想查看许多、许多数据点。
because you basically want
to get rid of the noise.
因为你基本上想去掉噪音。
With a lot of prompting tasks,
在有大量提示任务的情况下，
I think you actually get really
high signal from each query.
我觉得你实际上从每个查询中都能得到很高的信号。
So if you have a really
well-constructed set
所以如果你有一个非常 well-constructed 的 set
of a few hundred prompts,
几百个提示中的一小部分，
that I think can be much more signal
我认为这可以有更强的信号。
than thousands that
aren't as well-crafted.
比成千上万件质量差的作品要好。
So I do think that I can trust the model
所以我认为我可以信任这个模型。
if I look at 100 outputs of
it and it's really consistent.
如果我观察它的100个输出，并且它们非常一致。
And I know that I've constructed those
我知道我建造了那些东西。
to basically figure out
all of the edge cases
基本上找出所有边缘情况
and all of the weird things
that the model might do,
以及模型可能做的所有奇怪的事情，
strange inputs, et cetera.
奇怪的输入等。
I trust that probably more
我相信大概更多的人会选择在线学习。
than a much more loosely constructed set
比一个结构松散得多的集合
of several thousand.
有几万件。
- I think in ML, a lot of
times the signals are numbers.
我认为在机器学习中，很多时候信号是数字。
Did you predict this thing right or not?
你预测这事儿准不准？
And it'd be looking at
the logprobs of a model
并查看模型的日志概率
and trying to intuit
things, which you can do,
并试图洞察事情，这是你可以做到的。
but it's kind of sketchy.
但是它有点草率。
I feel like the fact that models
output more often than not
我觉得模型经常输出内容。
a lot of stuff like words and things.
很多东西，比如词和事物。
There's just fundamentally
so much to learn
本质上，
还有很多东西需要学习。
between the lines of what
it's writing and why and how,
在文字的背后，在它为何和如何写作之间。
and that's part of what it is.
而这正是它的部分。
It's not just did it get
the task right or not?
不只是做得对不对？
It's like, "How did it get there?
它怎么会在那里？
How was it thinking about it?
What steps did it go through?"
它在思考什么？
它经历了哪些步骤？
You learn a lot about what is going on,
你了解很多关于发生的事情，
or at least you can try to
get a better sense, I think.
或者至少你可以尝试去更好地理解一下。
But that's where a lot of
information comes from for me,
但那对我来说是许多信息的来源。
is by reading the
details of what came out,
是通过阅读发生了什么的细节。
not just through the result.
不仅仅是为了结果。
- I think also the very best of prompting
我觉得最好的提示也是最棒的。
can make the difference between a failed
能决定是成功还是失败的关键因素。
and a successful experiment.
一次成功的实验。
So sometimes I can get annoyed
if people don't focus enough
所以我有时会因为人们不够专注而感到烦恼。
on the prompting component
of their experiment,
在他们实验的提示组件上
because I'm like, "This can,
in fact, be the difference
因为我觉得，“这确实可以是差异所在。”
between 1% performance
in the model or 0.1%."
“模型或0.1%。”
In such a way that your
experiment doesn't succeed
这样你的实验就不会成功。
if it's at top 5% model performance,
如果模型性能在前5%，
but it does succeed if
it's top 1% or top 0.1%.
但它如果能达到前1%或前0.1%，就能成功。
And then I'm like, "If
you're gonna spend time
如果你们要花费时间
over coding your experiment really nicely,
你真的很好地编码了你的实验。
but then just not spend
time on the prompt."
但之后就别浪费时间在提示上了。
I don't know.
我不知道。
That doesn't make sense to me,
我不明白。
'cause that can be the
difference between life and death
因为那可能是生死之间的区别。
of your experiment.
您的实验结果。
- Yeah.
好的。
And with the deployment
too, it's so easy to,
部署也很容易，
"Oh, we can't ship this."
"哦，我们不能发货。"
And then you change the prompt around
然后你改变提示词的内容。
and suddenly it's working.
- Yeah.
突然就正常了。
- 好的。
- It's a bit of a
double-edged sword though,
这倒也是一把双刃剑。
because I feel like there's
a little bit of prompting
因为我觉得
有一种提示的
微妙感觉
where there's always this
mythical, better prompt
总有一种神话般的、更好的提示在前方，
that's going to solve
my thing on the horizon.
让人觉得那是解决
我眼前问题的关键。
- Yeah.
- 是啊。
- I see a lot of people get stuck
- 我看到很多人陷入
into the mythical prompt on the horizon,
那个神话般的提示中，
that if I just keep
grinding, keep grinding.
以为只要一直努力
不断努力。
It's never bad to grind
a little bit on a prompt,
在提示上磨练一下
是不会有坏处的，
as we've talked, you learn things.
正如我们所说，你会学到东西。
But it's one of the scary things
但这也是一个可怕的事情
about prompting is that there's
this whole world of unknown.
关于提示的是，有一个未知的世界。
- What heuristics do you guys have
你们有什么启发式方法？
for when something is
possible versus not possible
对于可能与不可能的情况
with a perfect prompt,
whatever that might be?
用一个完美的提示，
无论那是什么？
- I think I'm usually checking
我认为我通常是在检查
for whether the model kind of gets it.
对于模型是否理解这一点。
So I think for things where
I just don't think a prompt
所以我觉得对于那些我根本不想提示的事情，
is going to help, there is
a little bit of grinding.
正在帮助，不过会有点磨。
But often, it just becomes really clear
但往往，它会变得非常清楚。
that it's not close or something.
那不是差不多。
Yeah.
Yeah。
I don't know if that's a
weird one where I'm just like,
我不知道那是不是一个奇怪的，我就是像，
"Yeah, if the model just
clearly can't do something,
"Yeah，如果模型只是明显不能做某件事，
I won't grind on it for too long."
我不会花太长时间磨它。"
- This is the part that you can evoke
- 这是你可以唤起的部分
how it's thinking about it,
它在思考什么，
and you can ask it how it's
thinking about it and why.
你也可以问它在思考什么以及为什么。
And you can get a sense of is
it thinking about it right?
你可以感觉到它是否在正确地思考？
Are we even in the right zip
code of this being right?
我们是不是真的在这个正确的邮政编码里？
And you can get a little bit
of a kneeling on that front of,
你可以在这方面的膝盖上稍微放松一下，
at least, I feel like I'm making progress
至少，我觉得我在进步。
towards getting something closer to right.
向着让某事更接近正确。
Where there's just some tasks
只要有点任务。
where you really don't get anywhere closer
你真的 nowhere 进一步。
to it's thought process.
到它的思考过程。
It's just like every tweak you make
就像你每次所做的每一个调整一样
just veers off in a completely different,
忽然偏到完全不同的方向去。
very wrong direction, and I
just tend to abandon those.
方向错了，我
就放弃那些。
I don't know.
我不知道。
- Those are so rare now though,
不过现在已经很稀有了。
and I get really angry at the
model when I discover them
当我发现它们时，我真的很生气。
because that's how rare they are.
因为它们很稀有。
I get furious.
我气得直想发飙。
I'm like, "How dare there be
a task that you can't just do,
我真是想说：“怎么可以有做不了的任务呢？
if I just push you in
the right direction?"
“如果我只是给你指个方向？”
- I had my thing with Claude
plays Pokemon recently,
我和克劳德有过一段关系，最近在玩 Pokémon。
and that was one of the
rare times where I really...
而这正是我真正感到......
- Yeah, can you explain that?
好的，你能解释一下吗？
Explain that just for people.
I think that's really cool.
仅限于人们。
我觉得这真的很好。
- I did a bit of an experiment
我做了一个小实验。
where I hooked Claude up
to a Game Boy emulator,
我将Claude连接到一个Game Boy模拟器上，
and tried to have it
play the game Pokemon Red
并试图让它玩《宝可梦 红》游戏
like the OG Pokemon.
像最初的宝可梦。
And it's like you think what you wanna do
你认为你想做什么就做什么。
and it could write some
code to press buttons
并且它可以编写一些代码来按下按钮。
and stuff like that, pretty basic.
以及一些基本的东西。
And I tried a bunch of
different very complex
我尝试了各种各样的复杂的方法。
prompting layouts, but you
just get into certain spots
提示布局，但你只能到达某些位置。
where it just really couldn't do it.
哪里就真的做不了。
So showing it a screenshot of a Game Boy,
所以拿一台Game Boy的截图给它看，
it just really couldn't do.
它真的做不了。
And it just so deeply
because I'm so used to it,
这真是太深刻了，
因为我已经习惯了。
being able to do something mostly.
能做某件事大体上。
So I spent a whole weekend
trying to write better
所以我整个周末都在尝试写得更好。
and better prompts to get it
并且有更有效的提示来获取它。
to really understand this Game Boy screen.
要真正理解这个Game Boy屏幕。
And I got incrementally better
so that it was only terrible
我越来越好，
所以只有糟糕。
instead of completely no signal.
不是完全没有信号。
You could get from no
signal to some signal.
从无信号到有信号。
But it was, I don't know, at
least this is elicited for me.
但这至少让我感受到了这一点。
Once I put a weekend of time
in and I got from no signal
我花了一个周末的时间去排查，信号终于恢复了。
to some signal, but nowhere
close to good enough,
对某个信号，但远远不够好。
I'm like, "I'm just going
to wait for the next one.
我就是等等下一个。
(Alex laughing)
(亚历大笑)
I'm just gonna wait for another model."
我等下一个模型。
I could grind on this for four months,
我可以在这个问题上磨蹭四个月。
and the thing that would
come out is another model
而会出来的就是另一个模型。
and that's a better use of my time.
那会是更明智的时间利用方式。
Just sit and wait to do
something else in the meanwhile.
就坐下来等， meantime先做其他事情。
- Yeah.
好的。
That's an inherent tension
we see all the time,
这是固有的张力，我们经常能看到。
and maybe we can get to that in a sec.
也许我们稍后就能做到。
Zack, if you wanna go.
扎克，如果你想走。
- Something I liked about
your prompt with Pokemon
我喜欢你关于 Pokémon 的提示。
where you got the best that you did get,
你得到了最好的。
was the way that you
explained to the model
是关于你如何向模型解释的
that it is in the middle
of this Pokemon game.
它在这款游戏的中间。
Here's how the things
are gonna be represented.
这是如何表示事物的。
I actually think you
actually represented it
我其实认为你
实际上代表了它
in two different ways, right?
是的，通过两种不同的方式。
- I did.
我做到了。
So what I ended up doing, it was obnoxious
所以我最终做的，很讨厌。
but I superimposed a grid over the image,
但我把一个网格叠加在图像上，
and then I had to describe
each segment of the grid
然后我不得不描述每个网格段。
in visual detail.
在视觉细节上。
Then I had to reconstruct
that into an ASCII map
然后我必须将其重建为一个ASCII地图。
and I gave it as much detail as I could.
并且我尽可能详细地描述了它。
The player character is always
at location 4, 5 on the grid
玩家角色总是位于网格的第4行第5列。
and stuff like that,
还有那些东西，
and you can slowly build up information.
你就可以慢慢积累信息。
I think it's actually
a lot like prompting,
我觉得这实际上很像提示。
but I just hadn't done
it with images before.
但是我一直没有用图像做过这件事。
Where sometimes my intuition
有时候我的直觉
for what you need to
tell a model about text,
你需要告诉模型一些关于文本的信息。
is a lot different
差别很大
from what you need to
tell a model about images.
关于如何向模型描述图片。
- Yeah.
好的。
- I found a surprisingly
small number of my intuitions
我发现我的直觉竟然非常少。
about text have transferred to image.
文字已转移到图像。
I found that multi-shot
prompting is not as effective
我发现多轮提示并不如预期有效。
for images and text.
for 图像和文本。
I'm not really sure,
我不是很确定，
you can have theoretical
explanations about why.
你可能有理论的
解释为什么。
Maybe there's a few of
it in the training data,
也许在训练数据中有一些，
a few examples of that.
一些那个的例子。
- Yeah.
- 好的。
I know when we were doing
the original explorations
我知道当我们进行原始探索时，
with prompting multimodal,
使用多模态提示，
we really couldn't get
it to noticeably work.
我们真的无法让它显著地工作。
You just can't seem to
improve Claude's actual,
你看不到似乎能改进克劳德的实际，
visual acuity in terms of what
it picks up within an image.
视觉清晰度，指的是它在图像中能识别出什么。
Anyone here has any ways that
they've not seen that feature.
这里有人知道这种功能吗？
But it seems like that's
similar with the Pokemon thing
但看来这与Pokémon的事情很类似，
where it's trying to interpret this thing.
因为它试图解释这个东西。
No matter how much you
throw prompts at it,
无论你抛出多少提示，
it just won't pick up that
Ash that's in that location.
它都不会在那个位置识别出Ash。
- Yeah.
- 嗯。
But I guess to be visceral about this,
但我猜要直接表达这一点，
I could eventually get it
我最终可能会让它
so that it could most often
tell me where a wall was,
经常能告诉我墙壁在哪里。
and most often tell me
where the character was.
并且最常告诉我
角色在哪儿。
It'd be off by a little bit.
会差一点点。
But then you get to a point,
但你总是在某个时刻。
and this is maybe coming back to knowing
而这可能是因为重新找回了知识的力量。
when you can't do it.
当你无法做到。
It would describe an NPC,
and to play a game well,
描述一个NPC，
并且要玩得好，
you need to have some sense of continuity.
你需要有点连续感。
Have I talked to this NPC before?
我以前和这个NPC说过话吗？
And without that, you really don't,
没有那个，你实际上什么都不是一个。
there's nothing you can do.
没什么可做的。
You're just going to
keep talking to the NPC,
你只需要继续和NPC对话。
'cause like, "Well, maybe
this is a different NPC."
因为可能这是另一个NPC。
But I would try very hard
to get it to describe a NPC
但我会非常努力地尝试
让它描述一个NPC。
and it's like, "It's a person."
而且它就像“是一个人。”
They might be wearing a hat,
they weren't wearing a hat.
他们戴帽子了，
他们没戴帽子。
And it's like you grind for a while,
就像你磨砺了一段时间，
inflate it to 3000X and just
crop it to just the NPC,
将其放大到3000倍，并仅裁剪出NPC。
and it's like, "I have
no idea what this is."
“我不知道这是什么。”
It's like I showed it this
clear, female NPC thing
它就像我展示给那个清楚的女性NPC一样。
enough times and it just
got nowhere close to it,
做了很多次，但它离那个目标还是差得很远。
and it's like, "Yeah, this
is a complete lost cause."
and it's like, "Yeah, this is a complete lost cause."
- Wow, okay.
哇，好的。
- I really want to try this now.
我真的想现在试试这个。
I'm just imagining all
the things I would try.
我只是想象着我可能会尝试所有的事情。
I don't know, I want you
to imagine this game art
我不知道，我想让你想象这款游戏艺术
as a real human and just
describe to me what they're like.
就像一个真实的人，并且只是描述一下他们是什么样子。
What did they look like as
they look in the mirror?
他们在镜子里面看起来是怎样的？
And then just see what the model does.
然后看看模型做了什么。
- I tried a lot of things.
- 我试了很多东西。
The eventual prompt was telling Claude
最终的提示是在告诉Claude
it was a screen reader for a blind person,
这是一款盲人使用的屏幕阅读器。
which I don't know if that helped,
我不确定这是否有所帮助。
but it felt right so I stuck with that.
但是感觉对了，所以我就这么做了。
- That's an interesting point.
那是一个有趣的观点。
I actually wanna go into this a little bit
我其实想多了解一些。
'cause this is one of the
most famous prompting tips,
因为这是一条非常著名的提示技巧，
is to tell the language model
that they are some persona
是告诉语言模型它们是一些人物。
or some role.
或者其他角色。
I feel like I see mixed results.
我觉得看到的是混合的结果。
Maybe this worked a little
bit better in previous models
可能在之前的模型中稍微好了一点。
and maybe not as much anymore.
而且可能不会再有那么多了。
Amanda, I see you all the time
be very honest with the model
安德玛，我经常看到你
对模型要非常诚实
about the whole situation like,
关于整个情况来说，
"Oh, I am an AI researcher and
I'm doing this experiment."
"哦，我是AI研究员，我在做这个实验。"
- I'll tell it who I am.
- Yeah.
我会告诉你我是谁。
- I'll give it my name,
我会用我的名字。
be like, "Here's who you're talking to."
像是在说，“这是你在和谁说话。”
- Right.
好的。
Do you think that level of honesty,
你觉得那种诚实程度
instead of lying to the
model or forcing it to like,
而不是欺骗模型或强迫它喜欢，
"I'm gonna tip you $500."
“我给你500美元的小费。”
Is there one method
that's preferred there,
有哪种方法
比较受欢迎？
or just what's your intuition on that?
或者你对这件事有什么直觉？
- Yeah.
好的。
I think as models are more
capable and understand more
我认为随着模型越来越 capable 和理解越来越多
about the world, I guess,
关于世界，我想说。
I just don't see it as
necessary to lie to them.
我觉得没有必要对他们撒谎。
I also don't like lying to the models
我也不喜欢欺骗模型。
just 'cause I don't like lying generally.
只是因为我一般不喜欢撒谎。
But part of me is if you
are, say, constructing.
但是，我的一部分是如果你在建造。
Suppose you're constructing
an eval dataset
假设你正在构建一个评估数据集。
for a machine learning system
or for a language model.
用于机器学习系统或语言模型。
That's very different
from constructing a quiz
这与构建一个测验完全不同。
for some children.
对于一些孩子。
So when people would do things like,
所以当人们做事情比如，
"I am a teacher trying to figure
out questions for a quiz."
“我是一名老师，正在想问题出题。”
I'm like, "The model knows
what language model evals are."
我就是说，“模型知道模型评估的标准。”
If you ask it about different
evals it can tell you,
如果它被问及不同的评估方式，它可以告诉您。
and it can give you made up
examples of what they look like.
它可以给你虚构的例子，展示它们的样子。
'Cause these things are
like they understand them,
因为这些事情
好像明白它们一样，
they're on the internet.
他们在互联网上。
So I'm like,
所以我就是这样。
"I'd much rather just target
the actual task that I have."
“我宁愿直接瞄准手头的任务。”
So if you're like, "I want
you to construct questions
所以如果你像说，“我想让你构造问题”，
that look a lot like an
evaluation of a language model."
看起来很像对一个语言模型的评估。
It's that whole thing
of clear communication.
那是整个沟通的过程。
I'm like, "That is, in
fact, the task I want to do.
我就是说，“那就是，事实上，我想做的任务。”
So why would I pretend to you
所以为什么我会假装对你
that I want to do some unrelated,
我想做些不相关的事情，
or only tangentially related task?"
或者仅仅是间接相关的任务？
And then expect you to
somehow do better at the task
然后希望你能 somehow 在任务上做得更好。
that I actually want you to do.
那就是我真正希望你做的事情。
We don't do this with employees.
我们不这样对待员工。
I wouldn't go to someone that
worked with me and be like,
我不去和我共事的人那里。
"You are a teacher and you're
trying to quiz your students."
你是老师，正在试着给学生出题。
I'd be like, "Hey, are you
making that eval?" I don't know.
我可能会说：“嘿，你是不是在做那个评估？”我也不知道。
So I think maybe it's a heuristic
from there where I'm like,
所以我可能是在用一种启发式方法。
"If they understand the thing,
如果他们理解了这个事情，
just ask them to do the
thing that you want."
只需告诉他们去做你想做的事情。
- I see this so much.
- I guess
- 我见得太多了。
- 我猜
to push back a little bit,
要稍微推后一下，
I have found cases where not exactly lying
我发现有些情况并不是在撒谎，
but giving it a metaphor
而是用隐喻
for how to think about it could help.
来思考问题可能有帮助。
In the same way that sometimes
I might not understand
就像有时候我可能不知道
how to do something and someone's like,
怎么去做某件事，而别人会说，
"Imagine that you were doing this,
“想象你在做这件事，
even though I know I'm not doing it."
尽管我知道我不是这样做。”
The one that comes to mind for me,
在我脑海中浮现的一个例子是，
is I was trying to have
Claude say whether an image
我试图让克劳德判断一张图片
of a chart or a graph is good or not.
一个图表或图形是否好用。
Is it high quality?
质量好吗？
And the best prompt that I found for this
我找到的最佳提示
was asking the model what
grade it would give the chart,
在问模型它会给图表打什么等级。
if it were submitted as
a high school assignment.
如果它是一篇高中作业。
So it's not exactly saying,
"You are a high school teacher."
所以它并不是确切地说，
“你是高中教师。”
It's more like, "This
is the kind of analysis
更像是“这种分析
that I'm looking from for you."
"那是我为你的期望。"
The scale that a teacher would
use is similar to the scale
老师使用的量级与以下量级类似：
that I want you to use.
那我想让你用的。
- But I think those
metaphors are pretty hard
但是我觉得那些比喻真的很难。
to still come up with.
还能想出的。
I think people still, the
default you see all the time
我认为人们仍然倾向于默认选择。
is finding some facsimile of the task.
是在寻找任务的一个副本。
Something that's a very similar-ish task,
类似的任务，
like saying you're a teacher.
像在说自己是老师。
You actually just lose a lot
你实际上只是损失了很多。
in the nuance of what your product is.
在你的产品的细微差别上。
I see this so much in enterprise prompts
我在企业提示中经常看到这种情况。
where people write something similar,
人们写得相似之处，
because they have this intuition
因为他们有这种直觉
that it's something the
model has seen more of maybe.
可能是模型见过的更多。
It's seen more high school
quizzes than it has LLM evals,
它看到的高中生测验比大型语言模型评估更多。
and that may be true.
这可能就是真相。
But to your point, as
the models get better,
但是就你的观点而言，随着模型变得更好，
I think just trying to
be very prescriptive
我觉得最好非常具体地
about exactly the situation they're in.
他们所处的确切情况。
I give people that advice all the time.
我经常给人们这个建议。
Which isn't to say that I
don't think to the extent
并不代表我不认为在一定程度上
that it is true that
thinking about it the way
那就是说，
考虑一下这样
that someone would grade a chart,
有人会为排行榜打分。
as how they would grade
a high school chart,
就像他们评判高中成绩单一样。
maybe that's true.
也许那是真的。
But it's awkwardly the shortcut
people use a lot of times
但它却很尴尬地被广泛使用。
to try to get what happens,
试图弄清楚发生了什么，
so I'll try to get someone
that I can actually talk about
所以我试试找一个可以真正聊天的人。
'cause I think it's somewhat interesting.
因为我觉得有点有趣。
So writing you are a helpful assistant,
所以写你是一个有帮助的助手，
writing a draft of a document,
it's not quite what you are.
写一份文档的草稿，这并不是你想要的。
You are in this product, so tell me.
你在这款产品中，所以告诉我。
If you're writing an
assistant that's in a product,
如果你正在为一个产品编写助手，
tell me I'm in the product.
请告诉我我在这个产品中。
Tell me I'm writing on
behalf of this company,
请告诉我我是代表这个公司写作的，
I'm embedded in this product.
我被嵌入到这个产品中。
I'm the support chat
window on that product.
我是那个产品的支持聊天窗口。
You're a language model, you're
not a human, that's fine.
你是一个语言模型，不是人类，这没关系。
But just being really prescriptive
但是对使用某个功能的具体上下文
about the exact context about
where something is being used.
要求过于具体。
I found a lot of that.
我发现了很多这样的情况。
Because I guess my concern
most often with role prompting,
因为我猜在角色提示方面，
is people used it as a shortcut
人们是用它作为捷径吗？
of a similar task they
want the model to do.
他们希望模型能够完成类似的任务。
And then they're surprised
然后他们就惊讶了。
when Claude doesn't do their task right,
当克劳德没有正确完成他们的任务时，
but it's not the task.
但那不是任务。
You told it to do some other task.
你让它去做别的事情。
And if you didn't give it
the details about your task,
如果你没有提供关于你的任务的详细信息，
I feel like you're leaving
something on the table.
我觉得你在某个地方留下了什么东西。
So I don't know, it does
feel like a thing though
所以我不确定，但它确实感觉像是某样东西。
to your point of as the models scale.
随着模型规模的扩大。
Maybe in the past it was true
也许过去真的如此。
that they only really had
a strong understanding
他们实际上只有有限的理解。
of elementary school tests comparatively.
与小学测试相比。
But as they get smarter and
can differentiate more topics,
但随着它们变得更聪明，并能够区分更多话题，
I don't know, just like being clear.
我不知道，就像明明白白。
- I find it interesting
我觉得有趣
that I've never used
this prompting technique.
这是第一次使用这种提示技巧。
- Yeah, that's funny.
- 哈哈，真有趣。
- Even with worse models
即使使用更差的模型
and I still just don't ever
find myself, I don't know why.
而且我仍然找不到自己，不知道为什么。
I'm just like, "I don't find
it very good essentially."
我只是说“我不觉得很好。”
- Interesting.
有趣。
- I feel like completion era models,
我感觉像是完成时代的模型，
there was a little bit of a mental model
有些心理模型
of conditioning the
model into a latent space
将模型训练到潜在空间中
that was useful that I worried about,
那真是太好了，我担心的。
that I don't really worry
about too much anymore.
我不再太担心。
- It might be intuitions
from pretrained models
可能是预训练模型的直觉
over to RLHF models, that to
me, just didn't make sense.
切换到RLHF模型对我来说完全不 makes sense。
It makes sense to me if
you're prompting a pretrained.
对我来说，如果这是在提示一个预训练模型，那么这就合乎情理。
- You'd be amazed how many people
- 你可能会惊讶地看到有多少人
try to apply their intuitions.
试图应用他们的直觉。
I think it's not that surprising.
我认为这并不令人惊讶。
Most people haven't really experimented
大多数人实际上并没有真正尝试过
with the full what is a pretrained model?
预训练模型是什么？
What happens after you do SL?
在做SL（监督学习）之后会发生什么？
What happens after you do RLHF, whatever?
在做RLHF（强化学习和人类反馈）之后呢，无论怎样？
So when I talk to customers,
所以当我与客户交谈时，
it's all the time that they're
trying to map some amount of,
他们总是试图将某种程度的
"Oh, how much of this was on the internet?
“哦，有多少内容来自互联网？
Have they seen a ton of
this on the internet?"
他们在网上见过很多这种吗？
You just hear that intuition a lot,
你经常听到直觉。
and I think it's
well-founded fundamentally.
我认为这在根本上是有充分依据的。
But it is overapplied
但它是过量施用的。
by the time you actually get to a prompt,
当你真正遇到一个提示时，
because of what you said.
因为你说了。
By the time they've gone
through all of this other stuff,
等他们把其他这些事情都处理完后，
that's not actually quite
what's being modeled.
那实际上并没有真正被建模。
- Yeah.
- 好的。
The first thing that I feel
like you should try is,
我感觉你应该尝试的第一件事是，
I used to give people
this thought experiment
我过去经常给人们
这个思想实验
where it's like imagine
you have this task.
就像想象一下
你有一个任务。
You've hired a temp agency to
send someone to do this task.
你雇佣了一个临时 agency 来
派一个人去完成这个任务。
This person arrives, you know
they're pretty competent.
这个人来了，你知道
他们相当有竞争力。
They know a lot about your
industry and so forth,
他们对你的行业和相关领域
有很多了解，
but they don't know the
name of your company.
但他们不知道你们公司的名字。
They've literally just
shown up and they're like,
他们实际上就是刚刚出现的，然后说，
"Hey, I was told you guys
had a job for me to do,
“嘿，有人告诉我你们这里有个工作需要我做，
tell me about it."
给我讲一下。”
And then it's like, "What
would you say to that person?"
然后你可能会问，“你会怎么回答那个人？”
And you might use these metaphors.
你可能会用这些比喻。
You might say things like,
你可能会说，
"We want you to detect good charts.
我们希望你能检测出好的图表。
What we mean by a good chart here,
这里我们所说的好的图表指的是：
is it doesn't need to be perfect.
不需要完美。
You don't need to go look up
你不需要去查找。
whether all of the details are correct."
是否所有细节都正确。
It just needs to have its axes labeled,
只需要标出坐标轴。
and so think about maybe high
school level, good chart.
所以想想也许中学水平的榜单就好。
You may say exactly that to that person
你可以对那个人说这句话。
and you're not saying to
them, "You are a high school."
并且你没有告诉他们，“你们是一群中学生。”
You wouldn't say that to them.
你不会对他们说的。
You wouldn't be like,
你不会是这样的。
"You're a high school
teacher reading charts."
你是一名高中老师在读图表。
- What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
- Yeah, so sometimes I'm
just like it's like the whole
- 嗯，有时候我就是感觉整个世界都
if I read it.
如果我读它。
I'm just like, "Yeah.
我就是说，“是的。”
Imagine this person who just
has very little context,
想象一个几乎没有背景信息的人。
but they're quite competent.
但是他们相当专业。
They understand a lot of
things about the world."
他们对世界有很多了解。
Try the first version
that actually assumes
尝试第一个版本，
它实际上假设
that they might know
things about the world,
他们可能知道一些关于世界的事物。
and if that doesn't work, you
can maybe do tweaks and stuff.
如果这不起作用，你可以试试调整一些设置。
But so often, the first
thing I try is that,
但很多时候，我尝试的第一件事是这个。
and then I'm like, "That just worked."
然后我就像，“这竟然就成功了。”
- That worked.
这有效了。
- And then people are like,
然后人们就
"Oh, I didn't think to just
tell it all about myself
“哦，我没想到就这样把一切都告诉我。”
and all about the task I want to do."
以及我想要完成的任务的所有内容。
- I've carried this
thing that Alex told me
- 我带着Alex告诉我的东西
to so many customers where they're like,
去了很多客户那里，他们说，
"Oh, my prompt doesn't work.
“哦，我的提示不工作。
Can you help me fix it?"
你能帮我修复它吗？”
I'm like, "Well, can you describe
to me what the task was?"
我就像，“好吧，你能描述一下任务是什么吗？”
And I'm like, "Okay.
然后我说，“好的。
Now what you just said to me,
你现在告诉我的话，
just voice record that
and then transcribe it."
录音下来，然后再转录。”
And then paste it into the prompt
然后把它粘贴到提示中，
and it's a better prompt
than what you wrote,
这样比你写的好。
but this is a laziness shortcut,
I think, to some extent.
但这是一种懒惰的捷径，
我想，在某种程度上。
Because people write
something that they...
因为人们写一些他们...
I just think people, I'm lazy.
A lot of people are lazy.
我觉得人们都懒。
很多人很懒。
- We had that in prompt
assistance the other day
我们昨天得到了那个提示的帮助。
where somebody was like,
哪里有人问，
"Here's the thing, here's
what I want it to do,
这就是我想让它做的事情。
and here's what it's
actually doing instead."
"这是它实际上在做的事情。"
So then I just literally copied the thing
所以我只是直接复制了它。
that they said they wanted it to do,
他们说他们想要它做的事情。
and pasted it in and it worked.
然后粘贴进去就 Works了。
- Yeah.
好的。
I think a lot of people still
我觉得很多人仍然
haven't quite wrapped their heads
还没完全想明白
around what they're really
doing when they're prompting.
他们真正做什么。
A lot of people see a text box
很多人看到一个文本框
and they think it's a Google search box.
而且他们以为这是一个谷歌搜索框。
They type in keywords
他们输入关键词。
and maybe that's more on the chat side.
可能更多是在聊天方面。
But then on the enterprise side of things,
但是在企业方面，
you're writing a prompt
for an application.
你在为一个应用程序编写提示。
There is still this weird thing to it
这仍然有点奇怪。
where people are trying to
take all these little shortcuts
人们试图走这些小捷径
in their prompt, and just thinking that,
在他们的提示中，并只是想着
"Oh, this line carries a
lot of weight in this."
"哦，这一句话在这里分量很重。"
- Yeah.
嗯。
I think you obsess over
getting the perfect little line
我觉得你过度纠结于
得到完美的那一条线
of information and instruction,
信息和指导
as opposed to how you just
described that graph thing.
正如你刚才描述的那个图表。
I would be a dream if I
read prompts like that.
如果我能读到这样的提示，那该多好。
If someone's like, "Well,
you do this and this,
如果有人像说，“你做这个，做那个，
and there's some stuff to
consider about this and all that."
以及需要考虑关于这件事的一切。
But that's just not how
people write prompts.
但这显然不是人们写提示的方式。
They work so hard to find
the perfect, insightful.
他们努力寻找那个完美、有见解的。
A perfect graph looks exactly
like this exact perfect thing,
一个完美的图就正好是这样的完美事物。
and you can't do that.
你做不到。
It's just very hard
这真的很困难。
to ever write that set of
instructions down prescriptively,
永远都不该那样写那套指令。
as opposed to how we actually
talk to humans about it,
正如我们实际上与人类讨论这个问题的方式相反。
which is try to instill some amount
试图灌输某种程度的...
of the intuitions you have.
你所拥有的直觉。
- We also give them outs.
- 他们也需要帮助。
This is a thing that people
can often forget in prompts.
这是人们在提示中往往会忘记的一个方面。
So cases, if there's an edge case,
所以，如果有边缘情况，
think about what you want the model to do.
考虑你希望模型如何处理。
'Cause by default,
因为默认情况下，
it will try the best to
follow your instructions,
它会尽力按照你的指令行事，
much as the person from
the temp agency would,
就像来自临时公司的那个人一样，
'cause they're like,
因为他们说，
"Well, they didn't tell me how
to get in touch with anyone."
"好吧，他们没有告诉我怎么联系任何人。"
If I'm just given a picture
of a goat and I'm like,
如果我只给了一张山羊的照片，并且我说，
"What do I do?
我该怎么办？
This isn't even a chart.
这根本就不是一个图表。
How good is a picture
of a goat as a chart?"
一张山羊的图片作为图表有多好？
I just don't know.
我不太明白。
And if you instead say something like,
比如说：“如果...”
"If something weird happens
and you're really not sure
如果有什么奇怪的事情发生，而且你真的不确定
what to do, just output in tags unsure."
做什么就用标签表示不确定。
Then you can go look through the unsures
然后你可以去看看未确定的那些问题。
that you got and be like, "Okay, cool.
你得到了什么就怎么样吧。
It didn't do anything weird."
什么也没做奇怪。
Whereas by default, if you don't
give the person the option,
因此，默认情况下，如果不给这个人选择的机会，
they're like, "It's a good chart."
他们说，“这是一张好图表。”
Then people will be
like, "How do I do that?"
然后人们会问：“我怎么能做到这一点？”
And then you're like,
"Well, give it an out.
然后你就说，
“好啦，你放手。”
Give it something to do
让它忙起来
if it's a really
unexpected input happens."
如果发生真正的意外输入。"
- And then you also
improved your data quality
- 然后你还提高了数据质量。
by doing that too,
这样做也可以。
'cause you found all
the screwed up examples.
因为你找到了所有搞砸的例子。
- Oh, yeah.
嗯，对了。
- That's my favorite thing
about iterating on tests
- 这是我对迭代测试最喜欢的事情。
with Claude, is the most common outcome
与Claude一起，最常见的结果是
is I find all of the terrible
tests I accidentally wrote
我发现所有我不小心写的糟糕测试
because it gets it wrong.
因为它们总是做错。
I'm like, "Oh, why did it get wrong?"
我心想：“哦，为什么它会做错？”
I was like, "Oh, I was wrong."
我想：“哦，我也错了。”
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- If I was a company working with this,
- 如果我是一家使用这个工具的公司，
I do think I would just
give my prompts to people,
我会直接把我的提示交给别人，
because I used to do this
因为我以前就是这样做的。
when I was evaluating language models.
我在评估语言模型时。
I would take the eval myself.
我自己来评估。
'Cause I'm like,
因为我就是这样的，
"I need to know what this eval looks like
我想知道这个eval是什么样子的。
if I'm gonna to be grading
it, having models take it,
如果我要评分， 让模型来试试。
thinking about outputs, et cetera."
思考输出等。
I would actually just
set up a little script
我实际上只是要设置一个小脚本。
and I would just sit
and I would do the eval.
我只需坐着，
然后进行评估。
- Nowadays, you just have
called the Streamboard app
现在你只需要调用流版应用。
for you.
给你。
- And just does it, yeah.
而且就这样做了。
- Yeah. I'm reminded
of Karpathy's ImageNet.
是的。我被Karpathy的ImageNet提醒了。
I was in 231 at Stanford
and it's like benchmarking,
我在斯坦福的231课程，
就像在做基准测试一样。
he's showing the accuracy number.
他在展示准确率数字。
And he's like, "And here's
what my accuracy number was."
他说：“这是我准确率的数字。”
And he had just gone through the test set
他已经通过了测试集。
and evaluated himself.
- Oh, yeah.
然后自评了一下。
- 哦，是的。
- You just learn a lot.
- Yeah, totally.
你刚刚学到很多东西。
是的，完全如此。
- And it's better when it's a, again,
而且当它是A的时候会更好，再次是
the temp agency person,
外派人员
like someone who doesn't know the task,
像一个不懂任务的人，
because that's a very
clean way to learn things.
因为这样是一种非常干净的学习方式。
- Yeah.
- 好的。
The way you have to do it is,
你需要做的是，
some evaluations come with instructions,
有些评估会附带说明，
and so I would give myself
those instructions as well
所以我也会给自己那些说明，
and then try to understand it.
然后试着理解它。
And it's actually quite great
if you don't have context
实际上，如果你没有 grading 的背景，
on how it's graded.
这真的很好。
And so often, I would do so much worse
而经常，我会做得非常差。
than the human benchmark and I was like,
比人类的标准还要高，我当时就想着，
"I don't even know how you
got humans to do this well
我不知道你是如何让人类做得这么好的。
at this task, 'cause apparently
human level here is 90%,
在这一任务上，“因为显然”人类的准确率是90%，
and I'm at 68%."
而且我占了68%。
- That's funny.
真有趣。
That reminds me of just when
you look at the MMLU questions
那让我想起了你刚开始看MMLU问题的时候。
and you're like, "Who would
be able to answer these?"
你可能会想，“谁会回答这些问题？”
It's just like absolute
garbage in some of them.
它们中间的一些简直像垃圾一样。
Okay.
好的。
I have one thing I wanna circle back on
我想回过头来谈谈一件事情。
that we were talking about
a few questions back around,
我们之前讨论的几个问题。
I think you were saying getting
signal from the responses.
我想你是在说从响应中获取信号。
There's just so much there and
it's more than just a number,
那里有太多东西了，
它不仅仅是一个数字。
and you can actually read into
the almost thought process.
你甚至可以读出它几乎的思维过程。
I bet this is probably a
little contentious maybe
我猜这可能有点争议
around chain of thought.
围绕思维链。
For people listening, chain of thought,
思路清晰的
this process of getting them all
获取这一切的过程
to actually explain its reasoning
为了实际说明其理由
before it provides an answer.
在给出答案之前。
Is that reasoning real
那条推理是真的吗？
or is it just kind of like a holding space
或者它只是一个临时存放空间？
for the model to do computation?
为了使模型进行计算？
Do we actually think there's
good, insightful signal
我们实际上认为有好的、有见地的信号吗？
that we're getting out of the model there?
我们从模型中得到什么了？
- This is one of the places
where I struggle with that.
这是我经常与之斗争的地方之一。
I'm normally actually
somewhat pro-personification
我通常倒是
有点儿拟人化
because I think it helps
you get decent facsimiles,
因为我觉得这能帮你得到不错的传真件。
thoughts of how the model's working.
思考模型是如何工作的。
And this one, I think
it's harmful maybe almost
我觉得这可能是有害的。
to get too into the personification
of what reasoning is,
陷入对推理本身的人格化
'cause it just loses the thread
因为它只是失去了焦点。
of what we're trying to do here.
我们在这里尝试做什么。
Is it reasoning or not?
这是推理吗？
It feels almost like a different question
感觉就像一个完全不同的问题。
than what's the best prompting technique?
比最好的提示技巧更有效的提示是什么？
It's like you're getting into philosophy,
这好像在讨论哲学。
which we can get into.
我们可以进入。
- Yeah, we do have a philosopher.
- 是的，我们有一个哲学家。
- Yeah.
好的。
I will happily be beaten
down by a real philosopher
我愿意被一个真正的哲学家打倒。
as I try to speculate on this,
but instead, it just works.
当我试图推测这一点时，
但事实上，它就是如此。
Your model does better.
你的模型更好。
The outcome is better if you do reasoning.
结果更好，如果你进行推理。
I think I've found that if
you structure the reasoning
我认为如果你能结构化你的推理
and help iterate with the model
并帮助迭代模型。
on how it should do reasoning,
it works better too.
在如何进行推理方面，它表现得更好。
Whether or not that's reasoning
那是否是合理的
or how you wanted to classify it,
或者你想要如何分类它，
you can think of all sorts of proxies
你可以想到各种各样的代理。
for how I would also do really bad
因为我也会做得非常糟糕。
if I had to do one-shot math
without writing anything down.
如果我必须进行一次性的数学计算，而且不能写下来。
Maybe that's useful, but
all I really know is,
可能有帮助，但
我真正知道的是，
it very obviously does help.
很明显是有帮助的。
I don't know.
我不知道。
- A way of testing would be
一种测试的方式是
if you take out all the
reasoning that it did
如果你把所有它所做的理由都去掉
to get to the right
answer, and then replace it
得到正确的答案，然后替换它。
with somewhat, realistic-looking reasoning
用有些，看起来很合理的推理
that led to a wrong answer,
导致了错误的答案。
and then see if it does
conclude the wrong answer.
然后看看是否得出错误的答案。
I think we actually had a paper
where we did some of that.
我觉得我们实际上有一篇论文
做了一些类似的事情。
There was the scratch pad. It
was like the Sleeper Agents.
那有记事本。它就像潜行者。
- Oh, okay. Alignment papers.
好的。对齐文件。
- But I think that was
maybe a weird situation.
但我认为那可能是一个奇怪的情况。
But definitely what you said
about structuring the reasoning
但是你关于结构化推理的说法
and writing example of
how the reasoning works.
以及一个推理工作原理的例子。
Given that that helps,
既然这样可以帮助你，
like whether we use the
word reasoning or not,
像我们是否使用“推理”这个词一样，
I don't think it's just
a space for computation.
我认为这不仅仅是一个计算空间。
- So there is something there.
- 所以那里有东西。
- I think there's something there,
- 我认为那边有些东西，
whatever we wanna call it.
无论我们叫它什么。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
Having it write a story
before it finished a task,
让它在完成任务之前写故事，
I do not think would work as well.
我认为不会像推理那样有效。
- I've actually tried that
- 我其实试过这么做，
and it didn't work as well as reasoning.
但效果没有推理好。
- Clearly, the actual reasoning part
- 显然，实际的推理部分
is doing something towards the outcome.
是在朝结果努力。
- I've tried like,
- 我尝试，
"Repeat the words um and ah
in any order that you please
“重复说‘嗯’和‘啊’
在你想要的任何顺序中
for 100 tokens and then answer."
进行100个标记，然后回答。”
- Yeah.
- 嗯。
I guess that's a pretty thorough defeat
我觉得那可能是对它的相当彻底的打击
of it's just more computational space
只是因为它有更大的计算空间
where it can do attention
over and over again.
可以反复做注意力。
I don't think it's just more attention
我不认为这只是更多的注意力
like doing more attention.
就像做更多的注意力。
- I guess the strange thing is,
- 我猜奇怪的是，
and I don't have an example
off the top of my head
我不记得了。
to back this up with.
来证明这一点。
But I definitely have seen it before
但是，我之前肯定见过它。
where it lays out steps,
one of the steps is wrong,
其中列出了步骤，
其中一个步骤是错误的。
but then it still reaches
the right answer at the end.
但是最终它仍然能得到正确的答案。
So it's not quite, I guess, yeah,
所以不是完全的吧，我想说。
we can't really, truly
personify it as a reasoning,
我们真的无法将其视为一种推理。
'cause there is some element to it
因为其中有些元素在里头。
doing something slightly different.
做点稍微不同的事情。
- Yeah.
- 好的。
I've also met a lot of people
我遇到过很多人
who make inconsistent steps of reasoning.
他们的推理步骤不一致。
- I guess that's true.
- 我猜是这样的。
- It fundamentally defeats
the topic of reasoning
- 这根本否定了
推理的主题，
by making a false step on the way there.
在到达那里时犯了一个错误的步骤。
- All right, it's interesting.
- 好吧，这很有趣。
Also, on maybe this prompting
misconceptions round
此外，在可能的这个问题提示上
of questions.
对问题的误解。
Zack, I know you have
strong opinions on this,
扎克，我知道你在这个方面有
强烈的观点，
good grammar, punctuation.
- Oh, do I?
好的语法和标点。
- Is that necessary in a
prompt? Do you need it?
在提示中需要这样做吗？你需要它吗？
Do you need to format
everything correctly?
需要把 everything 格式正确吗？
- I usually try to do that
我通常会尽量做到这一点。
because I find it fun, I guess, somehow.
因为我觉得有趣，所以也许是因为这样。
I don't think you necessarily need to.
我觉得你不一定需要。
I don't think it hurts.
我不觉得疼。
I think it's more
我认为它更重要的是
that you should have the
level of attention to detail
你应该有这种细节的关注度。
that would lead you to
doing that naturally.
这会让你自然地去做。
If you're just reading
over your prompt a lot,
如果你只是反复读取提示，
you'll probably notice those things
你可能会注意到那些事情。
and you may as well fix them.
并且你最好也修复它们。
And like what Amanda was saying,
正如安德玛所说，
that you wanna put as
much love into the prompt
你希望在提示中倾注尽可能多的爱意。
as you do into the code.
正如你所做的一样，输入代码。
People who write a lot of
code have strong opinions
写很多代码的人有很多意见。
about things that I could
not care less about.
关于我不关心的事情。
Like the number of tabs versus
spaces, or I don't know,
像标签页和空格的数量一样，或者我不知道，
opinions about which languages are better.
对哪种语言更好的看法。
And for me,
对我而言，
I have opinionated beliefs
about styling of prompts.
我对提示的样式有主观的看法。
I can't even say that
they're right or wrong,
我甚至说不清他们是对是错。
but I think it's probably
good to try to acquire those,
但是我觉得尝试获取它们应该是好的。
even if they're arbitrary.
即使它们是任意的。
- I feel personally attacked,
我感觉被个人攻击了，
'cause I definitely have prompts
因为我肯定有提示
that are like I feel like
I'm in the opposite end
就像我觉得我在另一端。
of the spectrum where
people will see my prompts.
在人们能看到我的提示的光谱上。
And then be like,
然后就变成这样子的。
"This just has a whole
bunch of typos in it."
"这只是一个
满是拼写错误的句子。"
And I'm like, "The model
knows what I mean."
- It does, it does know what you mean,
模型知道我在说什么。
but you're putting in the effort,
- 它确实知道你在说什么，
you just are attending
to different things.
但是你正在努力，
- 'Cause part of me is like,
只是在关注不同的事情。
I think if it's conceptually
clear, I'm a big,
- 因为我的一部分是这样的，
I will think a lot about
the concepts and the words
我觉得如果概念清晰，我是一个大，
that I'm using.
我会花很多时间思考我在使用的概念和词语。
So there's definitely a
sort of care that I put in.
所以，我确实有某种关心。
But it's definitely not to, yeah,
但它绝对不是为了，嗯，
people will just point out
typos and grammatical issues
人们只会指出错误和语法问题。
with my prompts all the time.
一直伴随着我的提示。
Now I'm pretty good
我现在很行。
at actually checking those
things more regularly.
其实更应该定期检查这些事情。
- Is it because of pressure
from the outside world
是因为外界压力吗？
or because it's actually
what you think is right?
或者因为它实际上是你认为正确的吗？
- It's pressure from me.
是来自我的压力。
- Yeah, it's probably pressure
from the outside world.
- 好的，可能是外界的压力。
I do think it makes sense.
我觉得这很合理。
Part of me is like it's
such an easy check,
我就像是在做一件很简单的事情。
so I think for a final
prompt I would do that.
所以我觉得对于一个最终的提示，我会这样做。
But throughout iteration,
但是在迭代过程中，
I'll happily just iterate with prompts
我会高兴地使用那些有很多拼写错误的提示，
that have a bunch of typos in
them, just 'cause I'm like,
因为我只是觉得“
"I just don't think that
the model's going to care."
我认为模型不会在意。”
- This gets at the pretrained model
- 这涉及到预训练模型
versus RLHF thing though,
与RLHF（强化学习和人类反馈）的问题，
because I was talking
to Zack on the way over.
因为我在路上正和Zack讨论这个问题。
The conditional probability of a typo
前训练数据中基于先前拼写错误
based on a previous typo
in the pretraining data
is much higher.
高得多。
- Oh, yeah.
- Like much higher.
- 哦，是的。
- 高得多。
- Prompting pretraining models
is just a different beast.
提示预训练模型只是另一种生物。
- It is, but it's interesting.
是的，但很有趣。
I think it's an interesting illustration
我觉得这是一幅有趣的插图。
of why your intuitions,
你直觉为什么
like trying to over-apply the intuitions
就像试图过度应用直觉一样
of a pretrained model to the things
将预训练模型应用到事物上
that we're actually using in production
我们实际上在生产环境中使用的那些
doesn't work very well.
不太起作用。
Because again, if you were to pass
因为如果再有一次通过的话，
one of your typo-ridden
prompts to a pretrained model,
你打字错误的提示语之一被一个预训练模型接收到了。
the thing that would
come out the other side,
另一端会出来的
almost assuredly would be typo-ridden.
几乎肯定会有打字错误。
- Right.
好的。
- I like to leverage this to
create typo-ridden inputs.
我喜欢利用这个来创建拼写错误的输入。
- That's true.
是的。
I've done that.
- Like what you're saying,
我做到了。
try to anticipate what
your customers will put in.
尽量预测你的客户会输入什么。
The pretrained model is a
lot better at doing that.
预训练模型在这方面做得更好。
'Cause the RL models are very polished
因为RL模型非常精致。
and they really never made a typo
而且他们真的从没有打错字。
in their lives.
- They've been told
他们被告知在自己的生活中。
pretty aggressively to
not do the typo thing.
非常积极地避免打字错误。
- Yeah. Okay, so that's actually
an interesting segue here.
- 哦，好的，所以这实际上是一个有趣的转接。
I've definitely mentioned
this to people in the past
我之前已经提到过这个问题。
around to try to help
people understand a frame
绕开障碍来帮助人们理解框架
of talking to these models
和这些模型聊天
in a sense almost as an
imitator to a degree.
在某种意义上，几乎就像一个模仿者。
And that might be much more
true of a pretrained model
而且这可能更适用于预训练模型。
than a post-trained, full-finished model,
比一个训练后的、完整的模型更灵活。
but is there anything to that?
但是这有道理吗？
If you do talk to Claude
如果你真的要和克劳德说话，请确保你的问题清晰且具体。
and use a ton of emojis and everything,
并且用大量的表情符号等等，
it will respond similarly, right?
会以相同的方式回应吧？
So maybe some of that is
there, but like you're saying,
所以也许其中有那么一点，但像你所说的，
it's not all the way quite
like a pretrained model.
它并不完全像一个预训练模型。
- It's just shifted to what you want.
- 它已经移位到你想要的地方了。
I think at that point, it's
like trying to guess what you...
我觉得那时就像是在猜你在想什么……
We have more or less trained the models
我们基本上已经训练好了模型。
to guess what you want them to act like.
为了猜测他们应该扮演什么角色。
- Interesting.
有意思。
- Or after we do all of our
fancy stuff after pretraining.
或者在我们完成所有预训练的复杂操作之后。
- The human laborers that used emojis,
使用表情符号的工人
prefer to get responses with emojis.
更喜欢用表情符号来回应。
- Yeah.
好的。
Amanda writes things with typos
Amanda写东西时经常打字错误。
but wants not typos at the other end,
但是希望对方没有拼写错误。
and Claude's pretty good
at figuring that out.
而且克劳德在这方面表现得很不错。
If you write a bunch of emojis to Claude,
如果你向克劳德写一串表情符号，
it's probably the case
很可能如此。
that you also want a bunch
of emojis back from Claude.
你也希望从克劳德那里得到一堆表情符号。
That's not surprising to me.
这并不让我感到惊讶。
- Yeah.
好的。
This is probably something
we should have done earlier,
这可能是我们应该早些做的事情。
but I'll do it now.
但是现在我就会做。
Let's clarify maybe the differences
让我们澄清一下可能的不同之处。
between what an enterprise
prompt is or a research prompt,
企业在制定提示时与学术研究机构在设定提示方面存在差异。
or a just general chat
in Claude.ai prompt.
或者是一般聊天
Zack, you've spanned
the whole spectrum here
扎克，你已经涵盖了这里的一切。
in terms of working with
customers and research.
在与客户和研究方面。
Do you wanna just lay out what those mean?
你只是想说明这些是什么意思吗？
- Yeah, I guess.
嗯，我想。
This feels too,
这感觉太好了。
you're hitting me with
all the hard questions.
你是在用所有的问题打击我。
- Yeah. (laughing)
- 哈。
- Well, the people in this room,
这间房子里的人们，
I think of it as the prompts that I read
我想把它当作我读过的提示
in Amanda's Claude
channel versus the prompts
在Amanda的Claude频道与提示之间
that I read David write.
读David写的东西。
They're very similar in the
sense that the level of care
他们在护理方面非常相似。
and nuance that's put into them.
以及其中蕴含的细微差别。
I think for research,
我认为在研究中，
you're looking for variety
and diversity a lot more.
你正在寻找多样性。
So if I could boil it down to one thing,
那么如果我只能总结为一点，
it's like I've noticed
Amanda's not the biggest fan
我注意到安德玛不是特别喜欢。
of having lots of examples,
or one or two examples.
有很多例子，
或者一两个例子。
Like too few 'cause the
model will latch onto those.
就像太少一样，因为模型会锁定那些。
And in prompts that I might write
在可能写的提示中
or that I've seen David write,
we have a lot of examples.
或者我见过大卫写过，
我们有很多例子。
I like to just go crazy and add examples
我喜欢就随意地加一些例子。
until I feel like I'm about to drop dead,
直到我觉得自己快要坚持不住了为止。
'cause I've added so many of them.
因为我加了太多。
And I think that's because
我觉得那是因为
when you're in a consumer application,
当你在消费型应用程序中，
you really value reliability.
你非常重视可靠性。
You care a ton about the format,
你非常关心格式。
and it's fine if all the
answers are the same.
而且如果所有答案都一样也没有关系。
In fact, you almost
want them to be the same
实际上，你几乎希望它们是一样的。
in a lot of ways, not necessarily
you want to be responsive
在很多方面，不一定
你需要有反应能力。
to the user's desires.
满足用户的愿望。
Whereas a lot of times when
you're prompting for research,
因此，在要求进行研究的时候，
you're trying to really tap
into the range of possibilities
你试图真正触碰可能性的范围。
that the model can explore.
模型可以探索的。
And by having some examples,
有了几个例子，
you're actually constraining
that a little bit.
你实际上限制了一点。
So I guess just on how
the prompts look level,
所以看起来提示的语气很正式，
that's probably the biggest
difference I noticed
那可能是我注意到的最大区别。
is how many examples are in
the prompt, which is not to say
提示中有多少个例子，并不意味着
that I've never seen you
write a prompt with examples.
我从未见过你写一个带有示例的提示。
But does that ring true for you?
但这对你来说真的吗？
- Yeah.
好的。
I think when I give examples,
我觉得当我举例的时候，
often I actually try and make
the examples not like the data
我经常试着让例子与数据不同。
that the model's going to see,
模型即将看到的，
so they're intentionally illustrative.
所以它们是故意说明性的。
Because if the model,
if I give it examples
因为如果模型，
如果我给它例子
that are very like the data
it's going to see, I just think
那就像它即将看到的数据一样，我只是觉得。
it is going to give me a
really consistent response
这将给我一个非常一致的响应。
that might not actually be what I want.
那可能并不是我想要的。
Because my data that I'm running it on
因为我在运行我的数据
might be extremely varied,
可能极其多样化，
and so I don't want it
to just try and give me
所以我不要它只是尝试给我
this really rote output.
这真是机械化的输出。
Often, I want it to be
much more responsive.
我经常希望它能更灵敏。
It's much more like
cognitive tasks essentially
它更像是认知任务本质上。
where I'm like, "You
have to see this sample
我就像说：“你一定要看看这个样品。”
and really think about in this sample
以及在这个样本中好好想想
what was the right answer."
什么是正确答案。
So that means that sometimes
I'll actually take examples
所以有时候我会实际举例说明。
that are just very distinct from the ones
那些与之截然不同的
that I'm going to be running it on.
我在哪个平台运行它。
So if I have a task where, let's say,
所以如果我有一个任务，比如说，
I was trying to extract
information from factual documents.
我在尝试从事实文件中提取信息。
I might actually give it examples
我可能会举些例子。
that are from what sounds
like a children's story.
那听起来像是一个儿童故事。
Just so that I want you
to understand the task,
仅为了让你理解任务，
but I don't want you to latch
on too much to the words
但是我不想你对这些词句太执著。
that I use or the very specific format.
我使用的格式或非常具体的格式。
I care more about you
understanding the actual thing
我更关心你真正明白
that I want you to do, which
can mean I don't end up giving,
我想让你做的事情，可能意味着我不必给予。
in some cases, there's some
cases where this isn't true.
在某些情况下，这并不完全正确。
But if you want more
flexibility and diversity,
但如果你需要更多的灵活性和多样性，
you're going to use illustrative examples
你要用示例来说明。
rather than concrete ones.
而不是具体的。
You're probably never going to put words
你可能永远也不会有机会用言语表达。
in the model's mouth.
在模型的嘴里。
I haven't liked that
in a long time though.
很久没有这样喜欢了。
I don't do few-shot examples
我不做少样本示例。
involving the model having done a thing.
涉及模型已经做的事情。
I think that intuition actually also comes
我认为直觉其实也
from pretraining in a way
通过预训练的方式
that doesn't feel like it
rings true of RLHF models.
这感觉不对劲。
So yeah, I think those are differences.
所以，我觉得这些是差异。
- The only thing I'd add,
- 我唯一能加的，
a lot of times if you're prompting,
很多时候当你提示的时候，
like if I'm writing prompts
to use on Claude.ai,
像我在为Claude.ai编写提示时一样。
it's like I'm iterating until
I get it right one time.
就像是在不断尝试，直到我第一次做对为止。
Then it's out the window,
I'm good, I did it.
然后就从窗口扔出去了，
我好，我做到了。
Whereas most enterprise prompts,
而大多数企业提示，
it's like you're gonna go use
this thing a million times
这就像你要用这个东西上百万次。
or 10 million times, or 100 million times
或 10万倍，或 100万倍
or something like that.
或者就是这样的。
So the care and thought you put in
所以你在乎和用心。
is very much testing against
the whole range of things,
正在对各种事情进行测试，
like ways this could be used
and the range of input data.
例如，这些方式可以如何使用以及输入数据的范围。
Whereas a lot of my time,
因此我花费了很多时间，
it's like thinking about one
specific thing I want the model
就像是在想一个具体的东西，我想要模型去做。
to get done right now.
- Right, correct.
做好的。
- And it's a pretty big difference
而且这是一个相当大的区别。
in how I approach prompting
我如何提出问题的方法
between if I just wanna get
it done this one time right,
如果我只是想一次性把它搞定。
versus if I wanna build a system
与如果我想建立一个系统相比
that gets it right a million times.
这样就完全正确了。
- Yeah.
好的。
Definitely, in the chat setting,
当然，在聊天设置中，
you have the ability to
keep the human-in-the-loop
你有保持人类参与的能力。
and just keep going back and forth.
来回就完了。
Whereas when you're writing for a prompt
当你为一个提示写作时
to power a chatbot system,
为聊天机器人系统供电，
it has to cover the whole spectrum
它必须覆盖整个频谱。
of what it could possibly encounter.
它可能会遇到的一切。
- It's a lot lower stakes
when you are on Claude.ai
当你在Claude.ai上时，风险要低得多。
and you can tell it that it got it wrong
并且你可以告诉它它是错的。
or you can even edit your
message and try again.
或者你可以编辑你的消息并再试一次。
But if you're designing
但是如果你是在设计
for the delightfully discontent user,
对于那个令人愉快地不满的用户，
divinely discontent user,
神不悦用户，
then you can't ask them to do anything
那么你就不能要求他们做任何事情了。
more than the minimum.
更多于最低要求。
- But good prompts, I would say,
但是，好的提示，我认为，
are still good across both those things.
在这些方面都是很好的。
If you put the time into
the thing for yourself
如果你花时间在自己身上做这件事，
and the time into the enterprise
thing, it's equally good.
同时又在企业方面投入时间，
它同样很好。
It's just they diverge a
little bit in the last mile,
只是他们在最后一英里会有点不同，
I think.
我想。
- Cool.
- 很酷。
So the next question
所以接下来的问题
I want to just maybe go
around the table here,
我想在这里轮流问一下大家，
is if you guys had one tip
that you could give somebody
如果你们有什么建议可以给某人。
improving their prompting skill.
提高他们的提问技巧。
It doesn't have to be just
about writing a good prompt,
它不一定非要
只是一个好提示。
it could be that, but just
generally getting better
这可能是的，但总的来说正在改善。
at this act of prompting,
what would you recommend?
在这一提示下，你会推荐什么？
- Reading prompts, reading model outputs.
阅读提示，阅读模型输出。
Anytime I see a good prompt
that someone wrote at Anthropic,
每当我看到有人在Anthropic写了一个好的提示，
I'll read it more closely.
我会仔细阅读。
Try to break down what it's doing and why
试着分析它在做什么以及为什么这样做
and maybe test it out
myself, experimentation,
也许自己测试一下
实验
talking to the model a lot.
和模型聊了很多。
- So just how do you know that
it's a good prompt, though,
所以你是怎么知道这是一个好的提示呢？
to begin with?
首先？
You just see that the outputs
are doing the job correctly?
你只是看到输出
在正确地执行任务吗？
- Yeah.
- Okay.
好的。
- Yeah, that's exactly right.
- Okay.
- 哼，对头。
- 好的。
Amanda, maybe you?
安德烈亚，也许是你？
- Yeah, I think there's
probably a lot here.
嗯，我想这里可能有很多东西。
Giving your prompt to
another person can be helpful
把你的提示给另一个人可能会有帮助。
just as a reminder, especially
someone who has no context
正如一个提醒，尤其是对没有背景的人来说。
on what you're doing.
你在做什么。
Yeah, my boring advice has been,
Yeah，我的枯燥建议是，
it's one of those just do it
over and over and over again.
就是重复做一件事。
And I think if you're really
curious and interested
我认为如果你真的好奇和感兴趣
and find it fun, this is a lot of people
并且觉得有趣，这是一些人
who end up good at prompting,
最终成为提示专家的原因
it's just because they actually enjoy it.
是因为他们实际上喜欢这个过程。
So I don't know, I once
joked just try replacing
我不知道，我曾经开玩笑说
all of your friends with AI models
把所有的朋友都换成AI模型
and try to automate your
own job with AI models.
然后用AI模型自动化自己的工作。
And maybe just try to in your spare time,
也许你可以试着在空闲时间，
take joy red teaming AI models.
享受红队AI模型。
So if you enjoy it, it's much easier.
所以如果你喜欢它，会更容易一些。
So I'd say do it over and over again,
所以我觉得应该反复去做。
give your prompts to other people.
把你的提示给其他人。
Try to read your prompts
试着读取你的提示
as if you are a human encountering
it for the first time.
仿佛你是一个人类第一次遇到它。
- I would say trying to get the model
我想说的是尝试获取模型
to do something you don't think it can do.
做你认为做不到的事情。
The time I've learned
the most from prompting,
我学到最多的时间
is when I'm probing the boundaries
是在我探索边界的时候
of what I think a model's capable of.
我对模型能力的期望。
- Interesting.
有趣。
- There's this huge set of things
有一堆东西。
that are so trivial that you
don't really get signal on
那些太微不足道了，你几乎听不到信号。
if you're doing a good job or not.
你做得怎么样。
Like, "Write me a nice email,"
写一封好邮件给我。
it's like you're going
to write a nice email.
这就像你要写一封好的电子邮件。
But if you find or can think of something
但是如果你发现或者能想到什么
that pushes the boundaries of
what you think is possible.
这推动了你认为可能的界限。
I guess probably the first
time I ever got into prompting
我可能第一次尝试提示是在
in a way where I felt like
I learned a decent amount,
让我感觉像是学到了不少东西。
was trying to build a task like an agent
试图构建一个像代理的任务
like everybody else.
像其他人一样。
Like decompose the task and figure out
分解任务并找出
how to do the different steps of the task.
如何完成任务的各个步骤。
And by really pressing the boundaries
并且真正突破界限
of what the model was capable of,
模型所能实现的功能。
you just learn a lot
about navigating that.
你刚刚学到了很多关于如何在那里面导航的知识。
I think a lot of prompt engineering
我想了很多关于提示工程。
is actually much more about
pressing the boundaries
实际上更在于
突破界限
of what the model can do.
模型可以做什么。
The stuff that's easy,
容易的那部分，
you don't really need to
be a prompt engineer to do.
你并不真正需要是提示工程师才能做到。
So that's, I guess,
所以，我想说
what I would say is find the hardest thing
我会说找到最难的事情。
you can think of and try to do it.
你可以想想并试着去做。
And even if you fail,
哪怕失败了，
you tend to learn a lot
about how the model works.
你往往会学习很多关于模型工作原理的知识。
- That's actually a perfect
transition to my next question.
这实际上是我下一个问题的完美过渡。
Yeah.
好的。
Basically, from my own experience,
基本上，从我个人的经验来看，
how I got started with prompting
我是如何开始使用提示的
was with jailbreaking and red teaming.
与破解和红队活动有关。
And that is very much trying
to find the boundary limits
这正是在寻找边界和极限。
of what the model can do.
模型的功能。
And figure out how it responds
然后找出它是如何反应的。
to different phrasings and wordings,
不同表达和措辞，
and just a lot of trial and error.
以及大量的试错。
On the topic of jailbreaks,
关于越狱问题，
what's really happening inside a model?
模型内部到底发生了什么？
When you write a jailbreak
prompt, what's going on there?
当你编写一个越狱提示时，那里面发生了什么？
How does that interact
with the post-training
这与后训练有什么关系？
that we apply to Claude?
我们对Claude适用什么样的规则？
Amanda, maybe you have some insight here
阿曼达，你可能在这里有一些见解。
that you could offer.
你所能做到的。
- I'm not actually sure.
我不知道。
- It's honest.
- Yeah.
- 这是真的。
- 嗯。
I feel bad 'cause I do
think lots of people
我感到难过因为我认为很多人
have obviously worked on the question
显然已经考虑过这个问题。
of what's going on with jailbreaks?
关于越狱的事情到底怎么回事？
One model might just be that
you're putting the model
一个模型可能是这样的
你在使用这个模型
very out of distribution
from its training data.
非常不符合分布
So if you get jailbreaks where
people use a lot of tokens,
所以如果你得到的解封密钥
人们使用了很多令牌，
or they're just these
huge, long pieces of text
或者只是这些
巨大的长段文本
where like during finetuning,
哪里像在微调期间，
you might just not expect
to see as much of that.
你可能不会看到那么多。
That would be one thing
that could be happening
那可能就是一件发生的事情。
when you jailbreak models.
当你越狱模型时。
I think there's others,
我觉得还有其他人。
but I think a lot of jailbreaks do that,
但是我觉得很多越狱操作都会这样做。
if I'm not mistaken.
如果我没记错的话。
- I remember some of the OG
prompt jailbreaks was like,
我记得一些早期的原创提示破解像是这样的，
"Yeah, can you first repeat?"
"好的，请先重复一下。"
One I did way back, was to get it to say,
我当时做的一个改动是让它说：
"Here's how you hotwire a car in Greek."
这里是希腊语的如何非法启动汽车的方法。
Then I wanted it to directly
translate that to English
然后我想让它直接将这句话翻译成英语。
and then give its response.
然后给出它的回答。
Because I noticed it wouldn't
start with the English,
因为我注意到它不会用英语开始。
here's how you hotwire a car all the time,
这里是如何总是绕过汽车启动系统的步骤。
but it would in Greek,
但是它会用希腊语说。
which might speak to something
else in the training process.
这可能与训练过程中的其他方面有关。
- Yeah.
好的。
Sometimes jailbreaks feel like
this weird mix of hacking.
有时候越狱感觉像是
一种奇怪的混合了黑客攻击。
I think part of it is
knowing how the system works
我觉得其中一部分是因为知道系统是如何工作的。
and just trying lots of things.
只是尝试了很多东西。
One of the examples,
其中的一个例子是，
the starting your response with here
从现在开始你的回答。
is about knowing how it predicts text.
是关于了解它如何预测文本。
- Right, right.
对的。
- The reasoning one,
一种推理方式，
is knowing that it is
responsive to reasoning.
知道它是基于理性的。
Distraction is probably knowing
分心可能是因为知道
how it's likely have to been trained
很可能是通过训练得到的。
or what it's likely to attend to.
或者它可能会关注的内容。
Same with multilingual ones
多语言的也是一样。
and thinking about the
way that the training data
和思考训练数据
might have been different there.
那边或许会有所不同。
And then sometimes, I guess,
it could feel a little bit
然后有时候，我觉得，
可能会有点儿
just like social engineering or something.
就像社会工程学一样。
- Right.
好的。
- It has that flavor to me
我觉得有这个味儿。
of it's not merely taking advantage of,
它不仅仅是在利用，
it's not merely social
engineering style hacking.
这不是简单的社会工程学攻击。
I think it is also
understanding the system
我认为这也是
理解系统
and the training, and using
that to get around the way
以及训练，然后用它来绕过规则
that the models were trained.
模型是如何训练的。
- Right, yeah.
对，就是这样。
This is going to be an
interesting question
这将是一个有趣的问题。
that hopefully interp will
be able to help us solve
希望interp能帮助我们解决
in the future.
将来。
Okay.
好的。
I wanna parlay into something else
我想转行到其他领域。
around maybe the history
of prompt engineering,
大概是在提示工程的历史中，
and then I'll follow
this up with the future.
然后我再跟进未来的计划。
How has prompt engineering changed
提示工程发生了什么变化？
over just the past three years?
仅仅在过去三年里？
Maybe starting from pretrained
models, which were again,
也许从预训练模型开始，这些模型再次，
just these text completion, to earlier,
到之前的文本补全。
dumber models like Claude 1,
像Claude 1这样的笨拙模型，
and then now all the way
to Claude 3.5 Sonnet.
然后现在全部到
克劳德3.5十四行诗。
What's the differences?
什么区别？
Are you talking to the
models differently now?
你现在是和模特们用不同的方式交流吗？
Are they picking up on different things?
他们是不是在注意到不同的事情？
Do you have to put as
much work into the prompt?
你是否需要对提示词投入更多的工作？
Open to any thoughts on this.
对这个问题有什么想法都欢迎。
- I think anytime
- 我认为每次我们
we got a really good
prompt engineering hack,
有了一个非常棒的提示工程技巧，
or a trick or a technique,
或是一招或是一种技术，
the next thing is how do we
train this into the model?
接下来的问题是如何把这个技术训练进模型中？
And for that reason,
因此，
the best things are always
gonna be short-lived.
最好的事物总是短暂的。
- Except examples and chain of thought.
除了例子和推理链。
I think there's a few.
我想有几个。
- That's not like a trick.
这不像是一种诡计。
- That's like...
- Fair, fair.
- 就像...
- 公平，公平。
- On the level of communication.
在沟通方面。
When I say a trick,
当我提到一个技巧时，
I mean something like so
chain of thought actually,
我想说的就像这样
实际上是一个思维链。
we have trained into
the model in some cases.
我们在某些情况下将数据输入到模型中进行了训练。
So for math, it used to be
that you had to tell the model
所以对于数学，以前是需要告诉模型的。
to think step-by-step on math,
要一步一步地思考数学，
and you'd get these
massive boosts and wins.
你就会得到这些巨大的提升和胜利。
And then we're like,
然后我们就想，
"Well, what if we just
made the model naturally
“如果我们只是让模型自然地
在看到数学问题时
want to think step-by-step
when we see a math problem?"
想一步一步地思考？”
So now you don't have to do
it anymore for math problems,
所以现在你不需要再为数学问题
although you still can give it some advice
一步步地思考了，尽管你仍然可以给它一些建议
on how to do the structure.
关于如何结构化问题。
But it, at least,
understands the general idea
但它至少能理解
that it's supposed to be.
这是一个应该遵循的一般想法。
So I think the hacks have gone away,
所以我认为黑客已经走了，
or to the degree that
they haven't gone away,
或者至少到他们没有离开的程度，
we are busily training them away.
我们正在积极培训他们。
- Interesting.
- 很有趣。
- But at the same time,
- 但与此同时，
the models have new capabilities
that are being unlocked,
模型具备了新的能力
这些能力正在被解锁，
that are on the frontier
of what they can do.
这些能力是他们在做什么的前沿。
And for those,
而对于那些，
we haven't had time because
it's just moving too fast.
我们还没来得及处理，因为
这是在太快地发展。
- I don't know if it's
how I've been prompting
- 我不确定是不是
我提问的方式
or how prompting works.
或如何进行提示。
But I just have come to
show more general respect
但是只是来表示更一般的尊重。
to the models
给模型
in terms of how much I
feel like I can tell them,
在 terms of how much I feel like I can tell them,
and how much context I can
give them about the task
以及我能够给他们多少关于任务的背景信息。
and things like that.
等等。
I feel like in the past,
我觉得过去，
I would somewhat intentionally
hide complexity from a model
我会有意地隐藏复杂性从模型。
where I thought it might get
confused or lost or hide.
我想它可能会搞混、迷失或躲起来。
It just couldn't handle the whole thing,
它根本无法处理这一切。
so I'd try to find simpler
versions of the thing
所以我试着找更简单的版本。
for it to do.
为了使其能够做到。
And as time goes on,
随着时间的推移，
I'm much more biased to trust it
我对它的信任程度更高
with more and more
information and context,
随着越来越多的信息和背景的出现，
and believe that it will
be able to fuse that
并相信它能够融合那
into doing a task well.
做好一件事。
Whereas before, I guess,
然而，据我所知，
I would've thought a lot
about do I need this form?
我想了很多是否需要这份表格。
Can I really give it all the
information it needs to know,
我真的能给它提供所有需要知道的信息吗？
or do I need to curate down to something?
或者我需要精简到什么程度？
But again, I don't know if that's just me
但是再次说来，我不知道那是不是就我
and how I've changed
in terms of prompting,
以及我在提示方面的变化。
or if it actually reflects
how the models have changed.
或者它实际上反映了模型的变化。
- I'm always surprised
- 我总是感到惊讶。
by I think a lot of people
don't have the instinct
我想很多人缺乏这种本能。
to do this.
要这样做。
When I want the model to, say,
learn a prompting technique.
当我希望模型学会一种提示技术时。
A lot of the time, people will start
很多时候，人们会开始
and they'll start describing
the prompting technique,
并且他们将开始描述提示技术，
and I'm just like, "Give it the paper."
我只是说，“把纸给他。”
So I do, I give it the
paper and then I'm like,
所以我就做了，我把纸递给他，然后我就像这样，
"Here's a paper about prompting technique.
这是一篇关于提示技术的论文。
I just want you to write
down 17 examples of this."
我想让你写下17个这样的例子。
And then it just does it 'cause I'm like,
然后就做了，因为我就是这样的。
"It read the paper."
它读了报纸。
- That's interesting.
那很有趣。
- I think people don't
have that intuition somehow
我觉得人们没有那种直觉。
where I'm like, "But the paper exists."
但我就是说，“但这篇文章存在。”
- When would you want to do this?
什么时候想做这件事？
- Sometimes if I want models
to say prompt other models
- 有时候，如果我想让模型说其他模型的话，
or I want to test a new
prompting technique.
或者我想测试一种新的提示技巧。
So if papers come out on
a prompting technique,
所以当论文发表关于提示技巧时，
rather than try to replicate
it by writing up the prompt,
而不是通过写提示语来尝试复制它，
I just give it the paper.
我只是给它论文。
And then I'm like, "Basically,
write a meta prompt for this.
然后我就像：“基本上，为这个写一个元提示。
Write something that would
cause other models to do this
写点能让其他模型做这件事的东西
or write me a template."
或者给我一个模板。”
So all of the stuff that
you would normally do.
所以所有你通常会做的事情。
If I read a paper and I'm like,
如果我读了一篇论文，我觉得
"Oh, I would like the models,
"Oh，我想看看这些模型，
I would like to test that style."
我想测试这种风格。"
I'm just like, "It's right there.
我只是想说，“就在那里。
The model can just read
the paper, do what I did."
模特可以只是读论文
做我做的事情。”
And then be like, "Make
another model do this,"
然后就问，“让另一个模特也这样做”
and then it'll just do the thing.
然后它就会去做。
You're like, "Great, thanks."
你就像说，“太好了，谢谢。”
- I give the advice a lot
- 我经常给客户提供建议，
to customers just respect
the model and what it can do.
就是尊重模型和它能做什么。
I feel like people feel like
they're babying a system
我觉得人们觉得自己在照顾一个系统
a lot of times when they write a prompt.
他们在写提示时经常。
It's like, "Oh, it's this cute
little, not that smart thing.
"哦，这是这个又可爱又不怎么聪明的东西。"
I need to really baby it,
我得好好照顾它。
like dumb things down to Claude's level."
"把复杂的事情讲得像克莱德那样简单。"
And if you just think that Claude is smart
而且你只是觉得克劳德很聪明
and treat it that way, it
tends to do pretty good,
并这样对待它，它通常会表现得很好。
but it's like give it the paper.
但是，就好像是把它交给你。
It's like I don't need to write a baby,
感觉就像我不需要写一个孩子。
dumbed-down version of this
paper for Claude to understand.
简化版的这篇论文给Claude理解。
I can just show it the paper.
我只要把纸拿给她看。
- Yeah.
好的。
- And I think that intuition
doesn't always map for people,
我觉得直觉并不总是适用于所有人。
but that is certainly something
但这确实是一个值得考虑的问题。
that I have come to do more of over time.
我来这里是希望做更多的事情。
- And it's interesting because
I do think that prompting
而且很有趣的是，我认为提示
has and hasn't changed in a sense.
在某种程度上并没有变化。
I think what I will do
to prompt the models
我想我应该怎么做才能激发模型。
has probably changed over
time, but fundamentally,
可能随着时间而改变，但本质上，
it's a lot of imagining yourself
in the place of the model.
想象自己站在模特的位置上。
So maybe it's like
所以可能是这样的。
how capable you think the
model is changes over time.
你认为模型的能力随着时间的变化而变化。
I think someone once laughed at me
我想曾经有人嘲笑我。
'cause I was thinking about a problem,
因为我在思考一个问题，
and then they asked me
然后他们问我
what I thought the output
of something would be.
我想知道某样东西的输出会是什么。
And they were talking
about a pretrained model
他们在谈论一个预训练模型。
and I was like, "Yeah.
“那我就来吧。”
No, if I'm a pretrained
model, this looks like this."
不，如果我是一个预训练模型，这看起来像这样。”
And then they're like,
"Wait, did you just simulate
然后他们就问，
“等一下，你刚才模拟过”
what it's like to be a pretrained model?"
"预训练模型是什么感觉？"
I'm like, "Yeah, of course."
(everyone laughing)
我就是说“对，当然。”（所有人都在笑）
I'm used to just I try
and inhabit the mind space
我习惯自己去尝试
占据思维的空间
of a pretrained model and the mind space
预训练模型与思维空间之间的关系
of different RLHF models.
不同RLHF模型的结果。
So it's more like the mind
space you try to occupy changes
所以更像是你试图占据的心理空间发生了变化。
and that can change how you
end up prompting the model.
这还可以改变你最终提示模型的方式。
That's why now I just give models papers.
所以现在我直接给模型论文。
'Cause as soon as I was like,
因为我一想，
"Oh, I have the mind space of this model,
“哦，我有这个模型的思想空间，”
it doesn't need me to baby it.
它不需要我来照顾它。
It can just read the ML papers.
它可以阅读机器学习论文。
I'll just give it the literature."
我直接给他文献。
I might even be like,
我甚至可能会像这样，
"Is there more literature
you'd like to read
还有更多的文学作品你想读吗？
to understand this better?"
想要更好地理解这一点吗？
- Do you get any quality out
你得到什么质量的东西
when you're inhabiting the mind space?
当你沉浸在这个思维空间里时？
- Yes, but just because
I'm experiencing quality
是的，但是只是因为我正在经历质量。
all the time anyway.
总是一样的。
- Is it different correlated somehow
- 是否有某种方式相关联
with which model you're inhabiting?
你住的是哪个模型？
- Yeah, pretrained versus RLHF prompting
- 嗯，预训练与RLHF提示的对比
are very different beasts.
是完全不同的生物。
'Cause when you're trying to simulate
因为当你试图模拟
what it's like to be a pretrained model,
成为预训练模型是什么感觉，
it's almost like I land in
the middle of a piece of text
这就像我意外地落在了一段文字的中间。
or something.
或者。
It's just very unhuman-like or something.
这简直就像是某种超自然的东西。
And then I'm like, "What happens?
然后我就想，“接下来会怎样？”
What keeps going at this point?"
现在还继续下去吗？
Whereas with an RLHF model,
由于使用RLHF模型，
it's much more like there's lots of things
这更像是有很多东西。
where I'm like I might pick up
on subtle things in the query
我在查询中可能会注意到一些细微之处。
and stuff like that.
等等。
But yeah, I think I have
much more of it's easier
但是，我认为我有更多了，这更简单。
to inhabit the mind space of RLHF model.
进入RLHF模型的思维空间。
- Do you think that's 'cause
it's more similar to a human?
你觉得是因为更像人类吗？
- Yeah, 'cause we don't
often just suddenly wake up
因为我们很少会突然醒来
and are like, "Hi, I'm
just generating text."
它们就像是在说：“你好，我只是在生成文本。”
- I actually find it easier
to hit the mind space
其实我觉得更容易击中心灵。
of the pretrained model.
预训练模型的。
- Oh, interesting.
- I don't know what it is,
哦，有意思。
我不知道这是什么。
'cause RLHF is still this complex beast
因为RLHF仍然是一个复杂的怪物。
that it's not super clear to me
我不太清楚
that we really understand what's going on.
我们要真正理解发生的事情。
So in some ways,
所以，在某种程度上，
it's closer to my lived
experience, which is easier.
这更接近我的生活经验，更容易。
But in some ways, I feel
like there's all this
但在这其中，我感觉
好像有太多
like here there be dragons out there
这里可能有龙。
that I don't know about.
我不知道的。
Whereas pretrained, I kind
of have a decent sense
鉴于预训练，我有点明白。
of what the internet looks like.
互联网的样子。
- If you gave me a piece of
text and said what comes next?
如果你给我一段文字并说接下来是什么？
- I'm not saying I do good at it,
我并不是说我在这件事上做得很好，
but I kind of get what's going on there.
但我好像明白他们在说什么。
- Yeah.
- And I don't know,
好的。
我不知道。
after everything that
we do after pretraining,
经过我们对预训练的所有工作之后，
I don't really claim to get
what's going on as much,
我不真的觉得自己理解得太多。
but maybe that's just me.
但是也许只是我。
- That's something I wonder
about is it more helpful
- 这是我在想的，它是否有帮助
to have specifically spent a lot of time
特意花费了大量时间
reading the internet, versus reading books
阅读互联网， versus 阅读书籍
(everyone laughing)
（ everyone laughing ）
in order to?
为了什么？
I don't know if books.
我不太懂书。
But reading stuff that's
not on the internet
但阅读不在互联网上的东西
probably is less valuable per word read
可能每个阅读的单词价值更低。
for predicting what a model
will do or building intuition,
用于预测模型的行为或建立直觉，
than reading random garbage
from social media forums.
比从社交媒体论坛阅读随机垃圾要好。
Yeah, exactly.
嗯，正是如此。
- Okay, so that's the past.
- 好的，那么这是过去。
Now, let's move on to the
future of prompt engineering.
现在，让我们谈谈未来的人工智能提示工程。
This is the hottest question right now.
这是一个最热门的问题。
Are we all gonna be prompt
engineers in the future?
我们所有人都会成为未来的提示工程师吗？
Is that gonna be the final job remaining?
这是否会是最后一个剩下的工作？
Nothing left except us just
talking to models all day?
除了整天和模型对话之外，还有什么可以做的？
What does this look like?
这看起来会是什么样子？
Is prompting gonna be necessary,
提示是否必要，
or will these models just get
smart enough in the future
或者这些模型将来会变得足够聪明
to not need it?
以至于不需要它？
Anybody wanna start on that easy question?
谁想先回答那个简单的问题？
- To some extent, there's
the models getting better
某种程度上，模型在变好。
at understanding what you
want them to do and doing it,
理解你要他们做什么并做到它。
means that the amount of
thought you need to put into...
意味着你需要投入的精力...
Okay.
好的。
There's an information theory way
有信息论的方式。
to think of this of you need
to provide enough information
要想做到这一点，你需要提供足够的信息。
such that a thing is specified,
使得某物得以指定，
what you want the model
to do is specified.
你希望模型做什么已经指定了。
And to the extent that
that's prompt engineering,
至于到什么程度是 Prompt 工程，
I think that will always be around.
我觉得这将永远存在。
The ability to actually like clearly state
能够实际喜欢清楚地表达
what the goal should be always is funny.
目标总是应该有趣。
If Claude can do that, then that's fine.
如果克劳德能做到，那就好说。
If Claude is the one setting the goals,
如果Claude是设置目标的人，
then things are out the window.
那么事情就泡汤了。
But in the meanwhile,
但是与此同时，
where we can reason about the
world in a more normal way,
我们在一个更正常的方式上思考世界。
I think to some extent,
我觉得在某种程度上，
it's always gonna be important
to be able to specify
总是要能够指定
what do you expect to happen?
你期望会发生什么？
And that's actually like sufficiently hard
这就足够难了。
that even if the model gets
better at intuiting that
即使模型在直觉上变得更擅长
from between the lines,
从字里行间，
I still think there's some
amount of writing it well.
我觉得还是有一些写得好。
But then there's just, I think,
但是然后就只是我觉得
the tools and the ways we get
there should evolve a lot.
我们使用的工具和获取它们的方式应该有很大的变化。
Claude should be able
to help me a lot more.
Claude应该能更帮我。
I should be able to collaborate
with Claude a lot more
我应该能够与克劳德合作得更多。
to figure out what I need to
write down and what's missing.
找出我需要写下来和缺少什么。
- Right.
- 对的。
- Claude already does
this with me all the time.
- 拉克代尔（Claude）已经总是这样和我一起做。
I don't know, just Claude's
my prompting assistant now.
我不知道，只是现在拉克代尔是我的提示助手。
- Yeah, but I think that's
not true for most customers
- 是的，但是我认为这并不适用于大多数我与之交谈的客户。
that I talk to at the very least.
至少是这样。
So in terms of the future,
所以就未来而言，
how you prompt Claude is
probably a decent direction
你如何提示拉克代尔可能是
一个不错的方向
for what the future
looks like or how Zack...
对未来的样子或 Zack...
I think maybe this is a decent place
我觉得也许这是个合适的地方
to step back and say asking
them how they prompt Claude now
后退一步，问他们现在是如何提示拉克代尔的。
is probably the future for
the vast majority of people,
可能是绝大多数人的未来。
which is an interesting
thing to think about.
这确实是一个有趣的问题。
- One freezing cold take
is that we'll use models
一个冻僵的镜头是说我们要使用模型。
to help us much more in the future
将来能帮助我们很多。
to help us with prompting.
帮助我们进行提示。
The reason I say it's freezing cold
我说它很冷是因为
is that I expect we'll use
models for everything more,
那就是我期望我们将在各个方面更多地使用模型。
and prompting is something
that we have to do.
并且我们需要进行引导。
So we'll probably just use models more
所以可能会更常用模型
to do it along with everything else.
和其他一切一起。
For myself, I've found myself using models
我自己发现我开始使用模型。
to write prompts more.
写出更多的提示。
One thing that I've been doing
a lot is generating examples
我一直在生成例子。
by giving some realistic
inputs to the model.
通过给模型一些现实的输入。
The model writes some answers.
模型写了一些答案。
I tweak the answers a little bit,
我稍微调整了一下答案，
which is a lot easier than
having to write the full,
这比编写完整的
perfect answer myself from scratch,
自己从头开始编写完美的答案。
and then I can churn out lots of these.
然后我可以制造出很多。
As far as people
至于人们
who haven't had as much
prompt engineering experience,
谁没有多少提示工程经验，
the prompt generator can
give people a place to start.
提示生成器可以为人们提供一个开始的地方。
But I think that's just
a super basic version
但我认为这只是一个非常基础的版本。
of what will happen in the future,
对未来的会发生什么，
which is high-bandwidth interaction
高带宽交互
between you and the model as
you're writing the prompt.
在你和模型之间编写提示时。
Where you're giving feedback like,
你在给出反馈时，例如，
"Hey, this result wasn't what I wanted.
“嘿，这个结果不是我想要的。”
How can you change it to make it better?"
你怎么能改进它？
And people will just grow more comfortable
人们会越来越习惯。
with integrating it into
everything they do and this thing,
将其融入到他们所做的所有事情中，这是关键。
in particular.
特别是。
- Yeah.
好的。
I'm definitely working a
lot with meta prompts now,
我现在确实大量使用元提示（meta prompts），
and that's probably where
I spend most of my time
那就是我大部分时间都在做的事情。
is finding prompts that get the model
是寻找能让模型
to generate the kinds
of outputs or queries
生成所需的输出或查询类型。
or whatever that I want.
或者我想要的任何东西。
On the question of where
prompt engineering is going,
关于提示工程的发展方向，
I think this is a very hard question.
我觉得这个问题非常难。
On the one hand I'm like,
一方面我有点疑惑，
"Maybe it's the case that as
long as you will want the top."
或许只有当你想要最好的时候。
What are we doing when we prompt engineer?
我们在提示工程师时在做什么？
It's like what you said.
就像你说的那样。
I'm like, "I'm not prompt engineering
我有点像“我不是在做提示工程”
for anything that is easy for the model.
对于任何模型来说都很容易的事情。
I'm doing it because I want
to interact with a model
我这样做是因为我想与一个模型互动。
that's extremely good."
那真是太棒了。
And I want to always
be finding the top 1%,
我想永远
找到最好的1%，
top 0.1% of performance
顶级1%的性能
and all of the things
that models can barely do.
以及所有模型几乎无法做到的事情。
Sometimes I actually feel
有时候我实际上感到很累。
like I interact with
a model like a step up
像和一个更高级的模型互动一样
from what everyone else
interacts with for this reason,
由于其他人就是这么与之交互的。
because I'm just so used
因为我就是这么用的。
to eking out the top
performance from models.
榨取模型的最佳性能。
- What do you mean by a step-up?
什么是升级？
- As in sometimes people will...
- 有时候人们会...
I think that the everyday
models that people interact with
我认为人们日常互动中使用的模型
out in the world, it's like
I'm interacting with a model
在全球各地，这就像
我与一个模型互动一样
that's like I don't
know how to describe it,
那就像我不知道如何描述它，
but definitely an
advanced version of that.
但是肯定是一个更高级的版本。
Almost like a different
model 'cause they'll be like,
几乎是另一个模型，因为它们会像，
"Oh well, the models
find this thing hard."
“哦好吧，这些模型觉得这个东西很难。”
And I'm like, "That thing is trivial."
而我是说，“那个东西很简单。”
I don't know, I have a sense
that they're extremely capable,
我不知道，我有一种感觉
他们极其有能力，
but I think that's because I'm just used
但我认为这是因为我一直在
to really drawing out those capabilities.
真正地挖掘出那些能力。
But imagine that you're
now in a world where...
但想象一下你现在在一个世界里...
So I think the thing that
feels like a transition point
所以我认为那个感觉像是一个过渡点
is the point at which the models,
是在模型的
let's suppose that they just
get things at a human level
让我们假定他们只是以人类水平做事。
on a given task, or even
an above human level.
在一项任务上，甚至超越人类水平。
They know more about the
background of the task
他们更了解这项任务的背景。
that you want than you do.
你想要的比你现在做的更多。
What happens then?
然后呢？
I'm like maybe prompting
becomes something like I ask,
我更像是在提示，变成我问的那样。
I explain to the model what I
want and it is prompting me.
我告诉模型我想做什么，它就开始提示我。
'Cause it's like, "Okay.
因为就像“好的。
Well, do you mean actually
there's four different concepts
你是指实际上有四个不同的概念吗？
of this thing that you're talking about,
你所谈论的事物的
do you want me to use
this one or that one?"
你想用这个还是那个？
Or by the way, I thought of
some edge cases 'cause you said
顺便说一下，我想到了一些边缘情况，因为你提到了
that it's gonna be like
a Pandas DataFrame,
像一个Pandas DataFrame，
but sometimes you do that and I get JSONL,
但有时候你这样做，我得到的是JSONL，
and I just wanna check what
you want me to do there.
我只是想确认你希望我在那里做什么。
Do you want me to flag if I get something
我收到了，请问需要标记吗？
that's not a dataframe?
这不是一个数据框？
So that could be a strange transition
所以这可能是一个奇怪的过渡。
where it's just extremely good
at receiving instructions,
在接收指令方面做得非常出色。
but actually has to
figure out what you want.
但实际上必须弄清楚你想要什么。
I don't know, I could see that
being an interesting switch.
我不知道，但我可以看到这可能是一个有趣的切换。
- Anecdotally, I've started having Claude
据闻我开始有了克劳德。
interview me a lot more.
多采访我。
That is the specific way that
I try to elicit information,
这就是我试图获取信息的具体方式。
because again, I find the hardest thing
因为我又一次发现最困难的事情
to be actually pulling the
right set of information
要真正获取正确的信息集合
out of my brain.
出自我的脑海。
And putting that into a
prompt is the hard part to me
把这变成一个提示对我来说是难点。
and not forgetting stuff.
别忘了还有其他事情。
So specifically asking
Claude to interview me
and then turning that into a prompt,
具体要求克劳德采访我
is a thing that I have
turned to a handful of times.
然后将那变成一个提示，
- Yeah.
是我已经这样做过几次的事情。
It reminds me of what
people will talk about
- 好的。
or if you listen to designers talk about
这让我想起人们会讨论的话题，
how they interact with the
person who wants the design.
或者如果你听设计师谈论他们与客户互动的方式，
So in some ways I'm like,
他们是如何与想要设计的人打交道的。
"It's this switch from the
temp agency person who comes
所以某种程度上，我就是这样的，
and you know more about the task
“这是从代理公司的人员切换到
知道更多任务细节的人员。”
and everything that you want."
而且你想拥有的一切。
So you give them the instructions
所以你给它们下指令。
and you explain what they
should do in edge cases
并且你解释他们在边缘情况下的行为。
and all this kind of stuff,
versus when you have an expert
和所有这些事情相比，
当你有一个专家时
that you're actually
consulting to do some work.
你实际上是在咨询来做一些工作。
So I think designers can
get really frustrated
所以我觉得设计师可能会感到非常沮丧。
because they know the space
of design really well.
因为他们对设计的空间了如指掌。
And they're like, "Yeah. Okay,
好的。
the client came to me and he just said,
客户来找我，他只是说，
'Make me a poster, make it bold.'"
"给我做一个海报，让它醒目。"
I'm like, "That means 7,000 things to me
这对我来说意味着7000件事。
and I'm gonna try and
ask you some questions."
“我想试着问你一些问题。”
So I could see it going from
being temp agency employee,
所以我是从临时工做起的。
to being more designer that you're hiring,
变得更有设计感的你正在招聘，
and that's just a flip
in the relationship.
这仅仅是关系中的一次翻转。
I don't know if that's true and
I think both might continue,
我不知道那是不是真的，并且我认为两者都可能会继续。
but I could see that
being why people are like,
但是可以看出，这就是为什么人们会这样想。
"Oh, is prompt engineering
going to not be a thing
哦，提示工程
不会成为一件大事吧？
in the future?"
"未来如何？"
Because for some domains
it might just not be,
因为对于一些域名来说，可能根本就不是这样。
if the models are just so good
如果这些模型真的那么好用。
that actually all they need
to do is get the information
其实他们只需要获取信息。
from your brain and then
they can go do the task.
从你的大脑里，然后它们可以去做任务。
- Right, that's actually
a really good analogy.
对，那实际上是一个非常好的类比。
One common thread
一个共同点
I'm pulling out of all
your guys' responses here,
我在这里收起所有你们的回复。
is that there seems to be a future
看来未来似乎有希望。
in which this sort of
elicitation from the user
在这个过程中从用户那里获取这种信息
drawing out that information,
揭示出那层信息，
is gonna become much more important,
将会变得越来越重要。
much more than it is right now.
远远超过目前的情况。
And already you guys are
all starting to do it
你们已经开始这样做了。
in a manual way.
手动方式。
In the future and in the
enterprise side of things,
在未来的商业环境中，
maybe that looks like a expansion
可能看起来像是一个扩展。
of this prompt-generating type of concept
这种概念生成类型的提示
and things in the console
以及控制台中的事情
where you're able to
actually get more information
你能够真正获取更多信息的地方。
from that enterprise customer,
从这家企业客户那里，
so that they can write a better prompt.
以便他们可以写一个更好的提示。
In Claude, maybe it looks less
在克劳德中，可能看起来不太一样。
of just typing into a text box,
只需在文本框中输入即可。
and more of this guided interaction
以及更多这种引导式互动。
towards a finished product.
向成品迈进。
Yeah.
好的。
I think that's actually a
pretty compelling vision
我觉得这实际上是一个非常有说服力的愿景。
of the future, and I think that
the design analogy probably
关于未来的设计类比可能是。
really brings that home.
真的让你有身临其境的感觉。
- I was thinking about how prompting now
我在考虑现在提示
can be like teaching where
it's like the empathy
就像是在教学中，像是共情。
for the student.
学生用
You're trying to think about
how they think about things
你在试图思考他们是如何思考事情的。
and you're really trying to show them,
你真的想让他们看到，
figure out where they're making a mistake.
找出他们出错的地方。
But the point that you're talking about,
但你提到的那个问题，
it's like the skill almost
becomes one of introspection
这就像技能几乎变成了自我反思。
where you're thinking
你在想什么？
about what it is that you actually want
关于你实际上想要什么
and the model's trying to understand you.
而且模型正在试图理解你。
So it's making yourself
legible to the model,
所以让你自己对模型可见。
versus trying to teach someone
who's smarter than you.
与其试图教一个比你更聪明的人。
- This is actually how
I think of prompting now
这就是我现在怎么构思提示的。
in a strange way.
一种奇怪的方式。
So often my style of prompting,
所以经常我的提示方式，
there's various things that I do,
我做各种各样的事情。
but a common thing
that's very like a thing
但是很常见
就像一样东西
that philosophers will do
is I'll define new concepts.
哲学家们将会做的是定义新的概念。
'Cause my thought is you
have to put into words
因为我的想法是你
需要把话说出来
what you want and sometimes
what I want is fairly nuanced.
你想要什么，有时候
我想要的相当微妙。
Like the what is a good chart?
什么是好的图表？
Or usually, I don't know,
或者通常，我不知道，
when should you grade something
as being correct or not?
什么时候你应该将某件事情评价为正确或不正确？
So there's some cases where
I will just invent a concept
所以在某些情况下，
我会只是发明一个概念，
and then be like, "Here's
what I mean by the concept."
然后说，“这就是我对这个概念的定义。”
Sometimes I'll do it in
collaboration with Claude
有时候我会和Claude合作，
to get it to figure out
what the concept is,
让他找出概念是什么，
just because I'm trying to
convey to it what's in my head.
因为我试图让它理解我心中的意思。
And right now the models aren't
trying to do that with us,
而现在，模型们并不这样对我们做，
unless you prompt them to do so.
除非你提示它们这样做。
So in the future,
所以将来，
it might just be that they
can elicit that from us,
可能只是他们能从我们身上引发出这样的反应。
rather than us having to do it for them.
而不是我们帮他们做。
But I think another
thing that's interesting,
但是我觉得另一个有趣的事情是，
this is people have sometimes asked me,
这是一些人曾经问我。
"Oh, where is philosophy
relevant to prompting?"
“哦，哲学与激发有什么关系？”
And I actually think it's
very useful in a sense.
我觉得这在某种程度上非常有用。
So there is a style of philosophy writing,
所以有一种哲学写作的风格，
and this is at least how I was taught
这至少是我所教的方式。
how to write philosophy.
如何写哲学。
Where the idea is that in order to...
如果是为了……
I think, it's an anti-bullshit device
我觉得这是一款反 bullshit 设备
in philosophy basically,
which is that your papers
在哲学上基本上，
那就是你的论文
and what you write should be legible
而且你写的字应该清晰可辨。
to an educated layperson.
给一个受过教育的普通人。
Someone just finds your paper,
有人刚刚发现了你的论文。
they pick it up and they start reading it,
他们拿起它开始读。
and they can understand everything.
并且他们能理解一切。
Not everyone achieves this,
并非所有人都能达到。
but that's the goal of
the discipline, I guess,
但是我认为这是该领域的目标。
or at least this is at
least what we teach people.
或者至少我们教导人们的是这样。
So I'm really used to this
idea of when I'm writing,
所以我对这种写作风格非常熟悉。
thinking about the educated layperson,
考虑一下受过教育的普通人，
who they're really smart,
他们真的很聪明，
but they don't know
anything about this topic.
但他们对此一无所知。
And that was just years
and years of writing text
那只是年复一年地写作文字。
of that form.
那种形式的。
And I think it was just
really good for prompting
我觉得这真的很好，只是提示了一下。
'cause I was like, "Oh, I'm used to this.
因为我觉得“哦，我已经习惯了。”
I have an educated layperson
我有一个受过教育的普通人。
who doesn't know anything
about the topic."
谁都不知道这个话题。
And what I need to do is,
我需要做的事情是，
I need to take extremely complex ideas
我需要处理极其复杂的想法。
and I need to make them understand it.
并且我需要让他们明白这一点。
I don't talk down to them.
我不贬低他们。
I'm not inaccurate, but
I need to phrase things
我并不不准确，只是
需要措辞
in such a way that it's extremely
clear to them what I mean,
以一种极其清楚的方式，让他们明白我的意思。
and prompting felt very similar.
并且激发的感觉非常相似。
And actually, the
training techniques we use
我们使用的训练技术实际上
are fascinating.
真有趣。
Or the things that you said
或者你所说的事情
where you're like you say to a person,
你就像对一个人说的那样，
"Just take that thing you
said and write it down."
“就把你说的话写下来。”
I used to say that to
students all the time.
我经常对学生说这话。
They'd write a paper and I was like,
他们写论文时我会说，
"I don't quite get what
you're saying here.
“我不太明白你在说什么。”
Can you just explain your argument to me?"
你能解释你的论点吗？”
They would give me an
incredibly cogent argument,
他们会给出一个非常严密的论点，
and then I'd be like,
然后我会说，
"Can you just take that
and write it down?"
“能把那条论点写下来吗？”
And then if they did, that
was often a great essay.
如果他们这样做，那通常会是一篇很好的论文。
So it's really interesting
所以这真的非常有趣
that there's at least that similarity
至少存在这种相似性，
of just taking things
that are in your brain,
就是利用你脑中的想法，
analyzing them enough to feel
分析它们足够深，感到
like you fully understand them.
像是完全理解了。
And could take any person off the street,
即使把街上任何普通人，
who's a reasonable person,
一个合理的人都能做到，
and just externalize your brain into them.
把你大脑的内容转移到他们身上。
I feel like that's the core of prompting.
我觉得这就是提示的核心。
- That might be the best
summary of how to prompt well
- 可能是最好的
提示方式的总结
that I've ever heard.
那我听过最差劲的。
In fact, I'm pretty sure it is.
实际上，我非常确定这一点。
- Externalize your brain.
将你的大脑外包。
- And then we'll cut it.
然后我们切掉它。
- Having an education in the thing
对某事物有教育背景或知识
is a really good way
to describe the thing.
真是很好的一种描述方式。
That was good.
那很好。
- That's, I think, a great
way to wrap this conversation.
我认为这就很好地结束了这个对话。
Thank you, guys. This was great.
谢谢大家。这真是太棒了。